那是去年的【世界街舞大赛】
That's last year's Battle of the Year.
这是在法国举行的国际“霹雳舞”
It's an international b-boy competition held in France,
过去15年
which for the last 15 years
美国一直输
the United States has lost.
上周末, 我去演唱会
I went to a concert this past weekend,
我听到了一些高中的孩子
and I overheard some high school kids
说“霹雳舞”已不再酷
saying that b-boying was no longer cool
像他们父母那一代在跳的
and it was something their parents did.
这吓了我一跳
That scared me.
这把我吓坏了, 因为这家公司
It scared me because this company,
我建立的一切
everything I've built,
就是靠“霹雳舞”起家的
started off with b-boying.
在法国还是很酷
It's obviously still cool over in France.
他们政府赞助【世界街舞大赛】
The government subsidizes Battle of the Year.
是政府让“嘻哈”得以生存
The government is keeping hip-hop alive.
在俄罗斯还是很酷
Still cool in Russia,
德国
Germany,
韩国
Korea.
偏偏在这里不酷
But it's not cool here where it was founded.
这可以解释为什么
Which would explain why,
国内的销量下降
domestically, our sales are down.
商品、影片、门票、服装
Merchandising, record sales, ticket sales, apparel.
这是公司创始以来, 第一次
But for the first time in this company's history,
国际销售超过国内
international sales are exceeding domestic.
我们有麻烦了
We are in trouble.
想想看, 若是“霹雳舞”不再酷了
Think about it, if b-boying ain't cool,
“嘻哈”还能撑多久？
how long before hip-hop isn't cool?
对我们公司而言, 代表什么意思？
And what will that mean to our business, our company?
嘿哟！
Hey, yo!
起床！等等！
Wake up! Hold on!
太阳晒屁股了
Get your ass up.
等你死了就可以睡很久
Come on, man. You can sleep when you're dead.
进来
Coming.
唐帝？
Dante?
你的佣人忘了擦窗户吗？
See your maid doesn't do windows, does she?
你来干嘛, 兄弟？
What the hell are you doing here, man?
我打给你了, 你没接
I've been calling, you ain't been answering.
我最近很忙
I've been busy lately.
好啦, 动动你的屁股, 开门
All right, well, bring your busy ass over and open up this door.
我不是来探监的
This ain't no prison visit.
你看起来像大便
You look like shit.
如果你是来烦我的,  D. ..
Look, if you came here to sweat me, D...
我来给你个建议
Came here to make you a proposition.
要不要让我进去啦？
You gonna let me in or what?
好吧
Okay.
这老东西还能用吗？
This... This old thing work?
好... 放看看
All right. Here we go.
瞧瞧
Check this out.
日本对韩国的世界冠军赛
That's Japan versus Korea, world champions.
现在的“霹雳舞”不一样
I mean, b-boying ain't the same
跟我们那时跳的不一样
from back in the days when we were dancing, man.
我们参加过最屌的是那一场?
I mean, what's the farthest we ever had to go to battle,
布朗克斯？
the Bronx?
现在, 这些孩子都跑去日本、德国、法国比赛
Now these kids are battling in Japan, Germany, France.
【世界街舞大赛】又要到了
So, the Battle of the Year is coming up, right?
我赞助了美国队
And I'm sponsoring the US crew.
我的舞团名字是“无敌洛杉矶”, 这些孩子都不错
So my crew is called LA's Finest. Now, these kids are good.
他们有舞技, 但还不是最棒
Acrobatic, they got skills, but they're not great.
然而
Yet.
就缺一件
Only missing one thing.
你
You.
我要你当教练
I want you to coach the crew.
教练？
Coach?
现在, 我知道你需要钱, 所以...
Now, I know you need money, so...
这样吧, 签个名...
Here you go, check that out,
只要你愿意...
let me know if that meets your approval.
下个月就是自由式比赛
But the freestyle sessions are next month,
我需要你整队去参加
and I need you to prepare my crew for battle.
我是一个篮球教练...   没关系
I was a basketball coach. It doesn't matter.
教练就是教练, 你是我见过的最好的, 兄弟
A coach is a coach, and you were the best I've ever seen, man.
你行的!    我已经不再是从前的我
It's in your heart. I ain't that guy anymore.
跟我来吧, 让我们去看看孩子们,
Just come with me, let's go check out the boys,
如果你认为他们很烂, 你掉头就走
and if you think they suck, you walk away.
没有压力, 你还等什么？
No pressure. So what are you waiting on?
我不行... D.     说真的,
You don't want me, D. I mean, seriously,
你错过了多少次机会
how many opportunities do you have
会自动送上门, WB ？
come knocking at your window every day, WB?
我连自己的生活都一团乱
Can't even keep my own shit straight.
我不想站在这里
Look, I'm not gonna stand here
假装关心你是怎么过日子的
and pretend like I know what you're going through,
我才不在乎
'cause I don't.
拜托, 老兄, 你心里有团火
But, come on, man, that fire in your heart,
渴望着打赢胜仗
that need to win and the ability
感染你周围的人, 让他们相信
to infect those around you and get them to believe the same thing?
你仍然有那种能力,  不会失去它
Man, you still got that shit. Guys like you don't lose it.
你不能老是窝这里, 这不是你
Look, man, this right here, this ain't you.
我知道你的过去
You had trajectory.
坦白的说
And I'll be frank with you, man,
我们都知道,  她再也不会回来
You and I both know she's never coming back.
够了
You know what, man?
到此为止!    我错了
We're done here.  I was wrong.
看来, 我真的是来探监的
This was a prison visit.
你把自己关在这里
And this is your cell, man.
我们之间的差别
The only difference has been between my life and yours,
我开了一扇门
is that I made a life out of opening doors
你却把它关上
and you made one out of closing them.
发掘娱乐公司... 请稍等
Dig One Entertainment. Please hold.
发掘娱乐... 我可以帮你吗？
Dig One Entertainment. How may I help you?
WB！
WB!
欢迎来发掘娱乐公司
Welcome to Dig One, baby.
你好, D
What's up, D
真是令人印象深刻
It's impressive. So talk to me.
告诉我好消息, 你答应了吗？
Tell me something good, man. You in?
还没有
Not yet.
我要做些功课, 看看我是否能担任
I need to do some homework, see if I can even pull this off, all right?
跟我来
Follow me.
就是这样
That's it.
这四、五年来... 约100小时的影片
About 100 hours of footage, goes back four or five years.
还需要什么吗？
Need anything else?
一百个小时, 是吧？
A hundred hours, huh?
一壶咖啡, 三明治
Maybe a pot of coffee, couple sandwiches.
杯里只有咖啡？(没酒)
So that is just coffee in there, right?
嗯... 只有咖啡
Yeah. Just coffee.
好
Good.
你好好用功吧
Keep the good shit right here.
你喔~ D.
Come on, D.
不会那么快就见到成效
Can't plug the cork overnight.
我会在我的办公室
Doesn't work that way. I'll be in my office.
你点的一壶咖啡
Okay, got you a fresh pot.
在我下班之前, 要不要先帮你叫个便当？
Did you want me to order you any dinner before I punch out?
不用了, 谢谢
No, I'm all good, thank you. Yeah.
呦, 看看那些肘部旋转
Yo, look at those elbow spins.
真是烂招
That shit is nasty.
那年韩国人变强了
Koreans came strong that year.
韩国舞团像是超级英雄
Those K-boys are like superheroes.
你也是“霹雳舞团”？   还不算
You b-boy? Nah, I wish.
我的队不是想跳霹雳舞就可以加入的
My people are not exactly chosen when it comes to breaking.
什么意思, 你的队？    我是犹太人
What do you mean, your people? Jews.
陆续参加比赛
We're rhythmically challenged.
我们企图想找出族人的风格
We're stripped of our swag at the circumcision.
我也得接受现况, 我还只是个粉丝
I've made my peace with it. Anyway, I'm a fan.
期待美国队在BOTY夺冠
Be dope to see the US crew take the BOTYs.
什么是BOTY？   你跟我开玩笑吧？
What the hell is a BOTY? Seriously?
请坐, 你叫什么名字？
Have a seat. What's your name?
富兰克林-歪
Franklyn, with a "Y".
布雷克
Blake.
富兰克林-歪, 教教我吧
So, Franklyn with a "Y" fill me in.
BOTYs代表【世界街舞大赛】
The BOTYs stands for Battle of the Year.
是世界杯“霹雳舞”大赛
It's the world cup of b-boying.
这是街舞比赛中最重要的大赛
It's the premier event, the big daddy of them all.
它起源于90年代-德国
It started in Germany in the '90s,
现在在法国举办
but now it takes place in France.
法国？
Why France?
因为在法国跳舞比吃饭还重要
'Cause the only thing the French revere more than carbs is dance.
总之,  20个国家的顶级队伍争夺世界冠军
Anyway, 20 countries bring their top crew to battle for the world championship.
你这么帅的犹太孩子怎么会懂这个？
And a nice Jewish kid like you knows all this because?
在希伯来学校里他们也不会教你泡妞
They don't teach you how to pick up chicks at Hebrew school,
因为跳霹雳舞很酷
and breaking made me cool.
虽然我是犹太人, 但我的宗教是“嘻哈”
I mean, I might be Jewish, but my religion is hip-hop.
你看过电影“街舞开战”了吗？
You've seen Planet B-Boy, yeah?
没有
Afraid not.
我能请教你一些事吗？
Can I ask you something?
可以
Sure.
为什么唐帝要找你来当教练？
Why is Dante having you coach his crew?
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
电影“街舞开战”就像是我们的圣经
Planet B-Boy, it's like our bible.
影片记录着“霹雳舞”的现况
It's this dope documentary about what b-boying is now.
我能用一下？
Can I see that?
这个吗？   对!
What, this? Yeah.
这是什么东西？
What is this thing?
这是新的索尼平板电脑
It's the new Sony tablet.
产品的未来趋势
It's the future.
“街舞开战”, 从网路影城下载超过十亿次
Planet B-Boy, it's got a billion rentals on Netflix.
等我一下
Hold on.
瞧瞧
Check it out.
起床！起床！
Come on, wake up! Wake up!
没时间睡觉！做事！
No time to sleep! Work to do!
几点了?    九点钟
What time is it? 9:00.
你们搞了一整晚？
You been holed up in here all night?
一百小时的影片耶...
Hundred hours of footage, right?
下了功夫, 是吧？
Guess you did your homework, huh?
够了
Enough, anyway.
什么时候世界变了？
When did all this shit happen?
感觉你老了吗？
Feeling old yet?
一点点
Little bit.
这些家伙的舞蹈真是惊人
The moves these guys are pulling off are phenomenal.
韩国队更是烧烫烫
The Koreans are on fire.
我们需要帮我们的舞团也点把火
And we need some of that fire for our crew.
如何呀？你答不答应？
So what's up, man? We got a deal or what?
两个条件...     你说
Two conditions. Name them.
首先, 富兰克林当我的助理教练
First, I want Franklyn here as my assistant coach.
真的假的？  你要这小子？
For real? This guy?
嗯
Yeah.
好吧!  第二个呢？
All right, done. Second one?
写在这里
This right here.
合约上多加了点东西
Made a little addendum to your contract.
只要是钱, 都不是问题
If this is about money, I'll take care of it.
只是一句话, D.   你先看看
It's just one line, D. Just read it.
“如果要我当教练的话...... ”
"If I do this..."
我看不懂你这鬼画符...
I can't make this out, man. It's chicken scratch.
写什么？ "如果要我当教练的话...
What does that say? "If I do this,
就得按照我的方式走 "
"I got to do it on my own terms."
签名吧
Little place for your initials right there.
好吧
Okay.
你很难搞, 兄弟
You are a tough negotiator, my man.
一个小时后让我们去看看舞团
All right, let's go see the crew in about an hour.
嘿, 珍, 你好
Hey, Jan, how you doing?
我在忙
I'm doing busy.
我想找D？ 一会儿就好
Can I see D? it won't even take a minute.
我干嘛帮你？
And I would do that for you because?
因为我们是同事?  我会很感激
'Cause we're co-workers and I'd really appreciate it.
再试试
Try again.
因为我只是一个男孩, 站在一个美女面前
( 电影《新娘百分百》台词 )
'Cause I'm just a boy standing in front of a girl
请教她关于未来的人生
asking her to further his career.
我很喜欢那部电影
I love that movie.
你叫什么名字？  你不知道？
What's your name again? Seriously?
富兰克林-歪
Franklyn. With a "Y".
富兰克林-歪想见您
Franklyn with a "Y" is here to see you.
翻回第一页
Go back to the first one.
对不起,  我不是故意要打扰您
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to bother you.
没事, 请坐
No bother. Have a seat.
好! 选那个, 但是玫瑰要拿掉
Okay, let's go with that one, but kill the roses.
乐队的经理想要有玫瑰
The band's manager really wanted the roses.
好吧... 玫瑰拿掉
Right, killing the roses.
什么事？
What's up?
我只是想告诉您
I just wanted to tell you
我不知道他为什么要找我当助教
I didn't know anything about him asking me to take the coaching job.
你现在才跟我说你不想做？
You saying you don't want to do this now?
不, 我想做
No, I want to do it,
不是我唆使WB这么做的
but I didn't want you to think that I put WB up to it or something.
没人叫的动WB, 连我也不行
Listen, nobody puts WB up to anything, not even me.
是啊, 我只是想确定您和我是很酷的
Yeah, I just wanted to make sure you and I were cool.
酷？
Cool?
我的意思是, 您应征我进来, D
I mean, you hooked me up with this job, D,
我不想忘恩负义
and I don't want to seem ungrateful.
小兄弟, 我坦白跟你说
Look here, man, let me level with you.
我甚至于不知道你是谁
I don't even know who you are.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
您不知道？
Seriously?
我是富兰克林-歪
I'm Franklyn with a "Y".
你几岁？   到12月时就满23岁了
How old are you? I'll be 23 in December.
富兰克林-歪, 你知道这两个家伙是谁吗？
Franklyn with a "Y", do you know who these two guys are?
知道
Yeah.
你们是当初的创始者
Yeah, y'all were ground-breakers back in the day.
当初舞团刚起步时
When I started off with the crew,
我们被称为斗鸡舞团
we were called the Battle Troop Crew.
我们内斗, 比对抗外敌多
We battled each other more than we battled other crews.
直到WB出现
Until WB showed up.
像是从乔治亚洲领养来的孩子
Comes up as a foster kid from Georgia
一副乡巴佬的样子
with this country, hillbilly-type swag,
但他就是有本事
but it was something about him, man,
他整合了舞团
that he just unified the crew.
让大家团结在一起
He just knows how to bring people together.
“嘻哈”流行的初期
And this is in the early days of hip-hop
在白人开始搞饶舌和跳霹雳舞之前
back before white boys were rapping and b-boying.
都是黑人和拉丁美洲人的天下
That wasn't around back then. It was just black and Latino.
那是我们的天下
That's all we had.
当我们准备好组团出来斗舞时
So when we would show up to a battle, oh, man.
你知道吗？
But you know what?
他早就跨过种族的藩篱
When he'd leave that cipher,
已经分不清他是白猫还是黑猫
he went from white bread to Wonder Bread.
他就是这么赞
That's how good he was.
难怪他叫WB (白与黑)
Guess I know why you call him WB.
没错!
Oh, yeah.
既然他这么沉浸于中, 为什么要放弃霹雳舞？
But if he was so dope, then why did he stop breaking?
他有他想做的事
He wanted to do the right thing.
以前我们很穷
See, back in those days, man, we were all broke.
跳“霹雳舞”没啥钱可捞
There was no money in b-boying. Sure.
当他知道女友怀孕时
So, when he got his girlfriend pregnant,
他的叔叔介绍他去圣马可队, 当篮球助理教练
her uncle offered him an assistant basketball coaching job at St. Mark's,
他去了
and he took it.
等等, 圣马可队...
Wait, not St. Mark's that, that racked up
击败洲际冠军的篮球队？  对!
all those state championships? Yeah.
他就是当时赢球的总教练
And he was the head coach at the time that they did it.
后来他有回来吗？
Then what is he doing back here?
又重头开始
Starting over.
我不懂
I don't follow.
几年前
Couple years ago,
他的妻子和孩子出车祸死了
WB lost his wife and son in a horrible car accident.
彻底摧毁了他的家
Completely tore his world apart, man.
于是他就...
I mean, he just...
他选择逃避
He checked out.
我希望他已经准备好重新开始
And I'm hoping that he's ready to check back in.
如果我是对的
And if I'm right,
往后五周里, 你能从他那儿学到的
you're gonna learn more in five weeks from that man
比在这里混五年还多
than you ever would in five years in this place.
我敢保证
That I promise.
就算失败了, 起码我们试过了, 富兰克林...
If it doesn't work out, well, we tried, right, Franklyn
歪!
with a "Y"?
“ 改变态度, 改变人生 ”
Change how you think, change your life.
瞧
See?
D, 瞧瞧~ 法国佬
D, didn't I tell you? Bring on the French.
打你韩国仔的小屁屁
Bring on the punk-ass Koreans.
赞赞赞
I like that. Looking good.
干得好
I like what I see. Good job.
教练, 你有什么感想？
Coach, what do you think?
你看到我拍手了   你们都不错
You saw me clapping. You guys are good.
没有瞧不起你们
No disrespect, but aren't those
有跟在法国比赛时跳的不一样吗?
the same moves you guys brought to France?
跟在法国时跳的不一样呀
That wasn't anything like France.
我看过你们的录影画面
I've been watching your tapes.
欧洲赛, 地区赛
European tours, regionals.
虽然修改了排舞顺序
You've changed the sequencing, yes,
但是看起来跟四年前的舞蹈动作一样
but it's basically the same routine as four years ago.
D, 我说过请教练是没用的
D, didn't I tell you this coaching thing wasn't gonna fly?
用不着你来教我怎么做
You don't tell me shit. You understand?
我并不想跟你抬杠
I'm not trying to play the hard case with you,
我只是想让你知道, 我们有我们的玩法
but I just want you to know we do have other options.
他们是在威胁我吗？听起来很像, 对不对？
Are they threatening me? Sounds like a threat, right?
你在威胁我吗？   没有啦
Are you threatening me? Come on, man.
这是你们的教练   教练说了算
This is your coach. What Coach says, you do.
少啰嗦
End of story.
教练？
Coach?
来, 大家排成一列
All right, everybody line up right here.
来吧, 兄弟们
Come on, fellas.
好! 全都向右转
All right, everybody turn to the right.
抬头挺胸, 起步走!
Chins up, start walking.
我们去外面
Let's take this outside.
你到底在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
少跟我机机歪歪
Think they got options, right?
我找你来是要让他们更好
I brought you here to make 'em better,
不是直接赶他们出去
not kick 'em out into the street.
他们可能有点态度上的问题
They may have a little bit of attitude...
我才不管什么态度... 来呀!
I don't care about attitude. Bring it.
这些家伙被宠坏了,  D. 越来越不像样
These guys are stuck, D. They ain't getting any better.
他们组团多久了?  五年？
How long they been a crew, five years?
六年
Six years.
更糟
Even worse.
他们正面临了转捩点
They've hit the tipping point.
他们已经不想为了获胜而去奋战
They've stopped putting all their blood, sweat and tears into winning a battle
只想随便混一混
and started putting it into just not losing.
相信我, 兄弟, 我有办法
Trust me, man, I got a plan.
人都被你赶跑了
What you have is an empty room.
你要怎么玩
That's what you got.
好吧, 你有什么好办法?  说来听听
All right, what's your plan? Make it good.
愚蠢的行为一再的重复着
Insanity is doing the same damn thing over and over
还妄想会有不同的结果
and expecting a different result.
这就是我们一直在做的傻事
That's what we've been doing.
这就是为什么我们一直输,  D
It's why we can't compete, D.
人家都挑最棒的选手出来组团比赛
All of our competitors are gonna bring their best dancers,
但在美国, 我们只会挑一个城市代表队参赛
but the US, we send one crew from one city
顶多夹杂着两三个霹雳舞高手
with maybe two or three top-tier b-boys on it.
我们该做的是挑三拣四
What we should be doing is cherry-picking the top b-boys
从美国各地进行海选
from every crew in every city across America.
好吧, 我大概懂了
Okay, let me get this straight.
也就是说, 你想组个霹雳舞明星梦幻队？
So you're saying put together some kind of b-boy all-star team?
霹雳梦幻舞团
A b-boy dream team.
跟打篮球一样
We did the same thing in basketball,
霹雳舞也行
and we started that sport, too.
参加奥运之前
We were getting schooled in the Olympics
集合乔丹、魔术强森、伯德
till we put Jordan, Magic, Bird,
巴克利、尤因,  在比赛前进行集训
Barkley, Ewing on the court,
组成梦幻篮球队
our dream team.
那个梦幻蓝球队有时间搞
That dream team had time to prepare.
你要知道, 你也想那样组队
You do realize you're trying to put together
组一个新的舞团要花多久？
a whole new crew in what?
【世界街舞大赛】还有三个月吗?
Battle of the Year is in three months?
碰巧的是, 自由式比赛将在下周举行
Here's the beauty of it. Freestyle sessions are next week.
很多高手都会来
All the top crews are gonna be in town.
与其整修你那个洛杉矶破烂队
Instead of a tune-up for LA's Finest,
还不如搞个真正的国家代表队
why not turn it into a try-out for a national team?
当你大肆宣传你将赞助一个新的梦幻舞团
When you put the word out you're sponsoring a dream team,
他们就会成群结队而来
they'll come in droves.
这是一个千载难逢的机会
It's an opportunity of a lifetime.
所以这就是你的计划？
So that's your plan?
这是我的计划
That's my plan.
不成功变成仁
It better work.
听好了
All right, so listen up.
唐帝, 传说中的霹雳舞王, 现在的嘻哈大亨
Dante, the once legendary b-boy, now hip-hop mogul,
大肆宣传
is putting out a nationwide shout.
呦, 照过来... 注意听!
Yo, this is it. Pay close attention.
管你是大江、还是大海
Crews from sea to shining sea,
管你是东南、还是西北, 通通报给你听
north, south, east and west, this is for you.
唐帝大大正在寻找美国最棒的霹雳舞者
My man Dante is on the hunt for America's best b-boys
将代表美国参加世界冠军杯
to represent the US in the world championship.
没错, 他要挑选出一支梦幻舞团
That's right, he's gonna handpick a dream team.
想加入的人
You want to be a part of it,
就来参加自由式霹雳舞大赛
get down to that freestyle competition with Cross One,
不管你有啥过人之处
and if you think you got what it takes to represent
管你是红、白、蓝, 你最好秀出来 (美国国旗)
the red, the white, the blue, you'd better bring it.
- 好的, 泰伦斯    - 试音, 试音, 试音
- Okay, Terrence. - Check, check, check.
我的兄弟D大为了求得霹雳舞高手
My man D is prowling for b-boy gold.
如果你真是高手中的高高手
If your crew has what it takes,
你一定要来这里
you need to come on down here.
我们正在寻找高高高高手
We are looking for the best of the best.
我不在乎你怎么来的
I don't care how you get down here.
只要勇敢的秀出你的小屁屁
Just bring your ass on down.
首轮挑出的32名
Here's our first 32.
接下来怎么办？
So what now?
先了解一下他们的来历
Now we see what they're made of.
告诉我你的名字和你来自哪里
Tell me your name and where you're from.
我叫大眼仔, 来自沙漠之石队
Name's Sight, representing Desert Rock.
我是千瓦, 辛辛那提街头之王
This is Kilowatt, Cincinnati Street Kings.
骗子, 迈阿密的毒蛇舞团
Grifter, Miami Viper Crew.
巴比诺, 瑞普摇滚舞团, 巴尔的摩市
Bambino from the Rip Rock Crew, Baltimore.
重伤害, 佛罗里达州, 奥兰多
Mayhem, Orlando, Florida.
李阿多尼斯, 芝加哥
Lil Adonis from Chicago.
福利兹, 布朗克斯摇滚
Flipz, Bronx Rockers.
童童, 叛徒
I go by Kid. Rebel.
我们代表费城
And we're representing Philadelphia.
阿尼斯, 好莱坞, 喷射烟队 , 法国来的
Anis, Hollywood Jet Funk, via France.
敲敲, LA, 掐脖子舞团
Do Knock, LA Strangler Crew.
我是山鸡
The name's Rooster.
擅长亡灵之舞
I got the five elements of death,
舞步, 风格, 力道, 独创性和灵魂
footwork, style, power, originality and soul.
不懂, 你就别上舞台
If you ain't got that, don't even get in the ring.
你为什么要跳霹雳舞呢？ 霹雳舞是我的所有
So why do you break? Breaking is my everything.
对我而言是世界的全部
This means everything in the world to me.
我生命中最重要的事
It's the most important thing in my life.
这是自我体现, 我靠它呼吸生存
It's self-expression. I live it, I breathe it.
我一无所有, 直到跳霹雳舞
I didn't really have much, and then I found breaking.
阿富汗归国后, 我需要“霹雳舞”
After Afghanistan, I needed b-boying.
霹雳舞救了我
Breaking saved my... Life.
我唯一会的事
It's the only thing I got.
我是个霹雳舞者, 也是同性恋,
I'm a b-boy, and I'm gay,
很多人质疑这点
and a lot of people have issue with that.
想像一下, 如果你是犹太教祭司的孩子
Imagine you're the son of a rabbi
想要酷酷的跳舞
and you're trying to be cool and break.
你是犹太人的霹雳舞者
You're Jewish and a b-boy.
他可能是被领养的
He's probably adopted.
每个霹雳舞者都有个最终目标
A main goal that I think every b-boy has
【世界街舞大赛】
is Battle of the Year.
【世界街舞大赛】是像“霹雳舞”里面的麦加圣地
Battle of the Year is like the Mecca of b-boying.
这就像伊莱·曼宁赢得超级杯橄榄球赛
It's like Eli Manning winning the Super Bowl.
这就像霹雳舞奥运大会
It's like the Olympics to breaking.
【世界街舞大赛】是霹雳舞者的全部
Battle of the Year means... Everything to a b-boy.
没别的了
It's the only thing there is.
你凭什么可以加入这个舞团？
Why do you deserve to be on this crew?
梦幻舞团不可能没有我"骗子", 因为我就是行!
There is no dream team without Grifter. 'Cause I'm damn good.
我具有资质...
I have what it takes to be one of the...
有史以来最好的
Best ever. Ever?
我想加入舞团, 光荣返乡
I want to be on that team that brings it home.
比赛跳舞时你在想什么？
What do you think about when you battle?
我的焦点是, 如果我赢不了
My main focus is, if I don't win,
我得回到我原来的生活
I got to go back to my old life.
我的母亲...      “女霹雳舞”
My mother.     B-girls.
好到冒泡...       踢屁屁教训一下...
Being so damn good. Kicking ass.
我想的是  我是多么爱“霹雳舞”
I think about how much I love b-boying.
霹雳女孩
Yeah, b-girls.
首先, 我要感谢各位的光临
First of all, I want to thank you all for coming.
我们感谢你的努力  你们做的非常出色
We appreciate your efforts. You did a great job.
但我们只有22个位子
But we only have 22 spots to fill,
叫到名字请站起来
so please stand up when I call your name.
- 首先是.. "敲敲"
- First up is Do Knock. - Yes!
阿尼斯
Anis. Yes.
嘿, 让我听到我的名字
Hey, let me hear my name.
狙击手
Sniper.
好耶！
Oorah, yeah!
福利兹
Flipz. Yes.
骗子
Grifter.
叫到你没？兄弟, 还有机会
Did you hear your name? Man, we good.
李阿多尼斯
Lil Adonis.
千瓦
Kilowatt. Yes.
巴比诺
Bambino. Yeah.
王牌
Aces. Yeah.
重伤害
Mayhem.
吉乐汀   我就知道！
Gillatine. I knew it!
童童和叛徒
Kid and Rebel. Yo.
兄弟, 有我们两个
That's what's up. Both of us, man, both of us.
斯瓦特... 有!
Swat. A'ight.
- 阿斯达... 天才...
- Abbstarr. Flair. - Yeah!
哦, 宝贝, 赞！
Ooh, baby, yes!
达尼...  阿门...
Dani. Amen.
- 难搞的 - 我做到了
- Intricate. - I made it.
终于...
And finally...
山鸡
Rooster.
赞！
Yes!
没叫到名字的, 谢谢你的光临
If I did not call your name, thank you for coming.
上榜的, 找富兰克林报到
If I did, see Franklyn here.
先生们
And, gentlemen,
准备接受严苛的训练, 要更快, 更持久
be prepared to train harder, faster and longer
就在未来的九周
than humanly possible, 'cause over the next nine weeks,
最后只有13人能组成梦幻舞团
only 13 of you will make the final dream team.
就这样
That's it.
该死的
Damn.
为什么有铁丝网？
What's up with the barbed wire?
这到底是什么鬼地方？
What the hell is this place?
废弃的青少年感化院
It's an old abandoned juvenile detention center.
妈的, 我妈说对了   什么？
Shit, my mom was right. What?
她老是说, 我会被送来接受感化
She always said I'd end up in a place like this.
唐帝那么有钱      我们来这里做什么？
Dante makes mad money. What are we doing here?
教练选的
Coach picked it.
这里废弃后, 他来带过夏季篮球训练营
He used to teach summer basketball camp here after it closed.
你不是犹太兄弟会的人, 对吧？
Not exactly B'nai B'rith, right?
我们俩虽然是犹太人, 但不见得就是好朋友
Listen, man, just 'cause we're both Jewish doesn't mean we're best friends.
也对啦
Good stuff.
- 好烂的地方 - 我喜欢
- This place is nasty. - Looks good to me.
比我出身的地方还要好, 算是希尔顿饭店
Compared to where I'm from, this joint's the goddamn Hilton.
欢迎光临
Welcome, gentlemen.
这个美丽公园般的环境
This beautiful park-like setting
是你们未来几个月的新家
is gonna be your new home for the next few months.
宿舍在这边
Dorms are right through here.
搬进来住吧
Go ahead and drop your stuff and get settled in.
不会吧...  你是认真的？
Nah, man. Are you serious?
开什么玩笑  神经病
This is ridiculous. Crazy.
呦,  什么鬼地方？
Yo, what is this place?
教练, 我一直有些想法...
Listen, Coach, I was thinking on some ideas
打从我当你的助手以来, 当然我也不想被开除啦
ever since you made me your assistant. Well, I want to earn my keep.
我认为我们应该请人来编舞, 如果你真的很想
Anyway, I think we should get a choreographer if you're really serious
在【世界街舞大赛】中尽情挥洒的话
about making a splash at the Battle of the Year.
找个具有世界水准的编舞艺术家
Someone who's done world tours and worked with major artists.
你脖子上挂着什么, 富兰克林？
What's that around your neck, Franklyn?
这是我的教练哨子
It's my coaching whistle.
交给我
Let me have it.
为什么？   交给我
Why? Give it up.
我要靠这个哨子
It's more of a support whistle for your
来辅助教练的工作...      富兰克林
head-coach whistle, so... Franklyn.
区分助教与舞者的角色
It just separates me from the b-boys.
交给我...        不要这样啦...
Let's have it. Can I say no?
不要啦...     把哨子交给我!
I really want to say no. Give me the damn whistle.
不要
No.
还有别的吗？
Anything else?
教练的宿舍在哪里？
Where's the coaches' quarters?
在那里, 但你会跟他们住在一起
Over there, but you'll be staying with them.
真的假的？
Seriously?
听好了！
Listen up!
离【世界街舞大赛】剩三个月了
Battle of the Year is three months away.
花点时间想想
Take a moment, think about that.
在三个月内
In three months,
有9个人会被淘汰
nine of you will be sitting back on your couches
其他13位将代表美国
while the other 13 are in France, representing America.
站上国际的舞台
Center stage in a global arena.
命运掌握在你手里
Choice is yours.
你付出了努力
You do this right,
生活将会大大的不同
nothing in your life will ever be the same.
我不是你们的朋友
Don't make the mistake of thinking I'm your friend.
我不是
I'm not.
我在这里唯一的目的
I'm here for one purpose.
我会用任何手段把你们组成一个团队
Turn you into a team by whatever means I deem necessary, period.
因为现在, 在韩国、日本
'Cause right now, in Korea, Japan,
法国、俄罗斯、遍布世界各地,
France, Russia, all over the world,
舞者每天训练7个小时
guys are training 24/7
因为他们想赢得【世界街舞大赛】
'cause they want to win the Battle of the Year.
问题是, 你呢？
The question is, do you?
规则很简单, 清晨6点开始训练
Our rules are simple. Practice starts at 6:00 a.m.
清晨6点？
6:00 a.m.? 6:00 a.m.?
你敢在6点01分才出现的话...
You come at 6:01...
淘汰！
...you will be gone!
我们每天训练12小时
We train 12 hours a day, every day.
没有假日
God takes Sundays off, we don't.
没时间了
We ain't got time.
这里就是你的世界
This facility will become your world.
敢跑出去鬼混的话就淘汰!
Step outside that world, you will be gone.
不按照我的规矩来... 就淘汰!
Bitch about my simple rules, you will be gone.
嘿, 教练
Hey, Coach.
想清楚再发问
Ask me some wise-ass question
我说会淘汰!  就会淘汰!
about "you will be gone," and you will be gone.
接下来的每个周五
Over each of the next nine Fridays,
我会给被淘汰的人
I'll be handing one of you one of these.
一张公车票
Bus pass.
送你回老乡
Take you back to wherever it is you came from.
你将会消失在我眼前
And you will be gone.
教练
Coach. Yeah.
明天是星期五...      对啊!
Tomorrow's Friday. That's correct.
明天, 马上就要淘汰一个
And tomorrow, one of you will be gone.
淘汰!
You will be gone.
哟, 瞧瞧, 孩子
Yo, check that out, son.
什么？
What?
这就是每个人都在争夺的... 派?
This is what everybody's battling for. Pie?
是啊, 派
Yeah, pie.
22条饥饿的狗, 僧多派少
Twenty-two starving dogs and not enough to go around.
我得到了我的
I got mine.
我知道, 我知道, 我说真的
I know, I know, I got it. No, I'm serious. Focus.
不要跟任何人说话, 不看任何人
Don't talk to anybody, don't look at nobody.
只有我们, 双重麻烦, 双重麻烦
Just us, double trouble. Right, double trouble.
你好啊, 童童？  你好啊, 敲敲？
What's up, Kid? What's up, Do Knock?
呦, 我只是打招呼？你太认真？
Yo, what did I just say, man? Are you serious?
兄弟, 他很酷
Come on, man, he's cool.
耶, 香草脆皮牛排淋上白酒收干酱汁
Yay, herb-crusted shank steak in a white wine reduction sauce.
用餐愉快, 兄弟们
Bon appetit, guys.
我们有误会吗？
We got a problem?
没有啊
I don't have a problem.
那为何你不愿意跟我一起用餐？
Why'd you get up when I sat down?
兄弟, 我习惯独来独往
Listen, man, where I'm from, we don't ask and you don't tell.
适应一下
You should try it.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
满意吗？
Are we good?
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
活像是洛杉矶血帮和瘸帮的帮派之战
This is like Fame, but with Bloods and Crips.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
22头狮子关在笼子里, 伤亡难免
Put 22 lions in a cage, someone's bound to get bit.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
我去喝一杯, 由你接管
I'm gonna have a drink. Take over.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
11点上床睡觉
Have 'em in their rooms by 11:00
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
叫他们洗自己的餐具
and make sure they clean up their trays.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
我自己搞定吗？
Me alone?
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
我怕我叫不动啊
But I haven't even established dominance yet.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
如果他们打起来呢？
What if they start throwing punches?
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
尽量不要被打到
Try not to get hit.
高清电影、美剧、动画片、纪录片硬盘拷贝
＝＝＝＝全球高清第①家＝＝＝＝
目录下载：http://13811115888.ys168.com
QQ：56491534
酷
Cool.
那只好发一发香烟免得被打
I'll just be here trading cigarettes for protection.
你跑去喝一杯, 还真是有益身心
You're gonna have a drink alone. That's healthy.
美国的“霹雳舞团”, 他们的特色就是
The US b-boys, they are mostly known for having
太着重于个人的舞技表现
a lot of individual skills for battling.
他们必须整合团队的力量
They need to get together as a crew and also overcome
克服大多数团员自大的问题
that ego problem that most of the b-boys have.
不然会很惨
It's disastrous.
好险
Sweet.
呦
Yo.
想成为第一个被淘汰的吗？
Trying to be the first one gone?
抱歉
Sorry.
福利兹
Flipz.
拿一件
Grab a pair.
呦！
Yo!
梦幻队服？
Dream Team sweats?
屌！
Sick!
你为什么迟到,  福利兹？哟, 运动服, 这是什么？
Why you late, Flipz? Yo, nice sweats, but what are these?
婴儿服？很可爱, 你要穿去法国吗？
Baby Gap? That's cute. You think you can take that to France?
兄弟, 我刚到这里
Man, I just got here.
看看你的胸前的口袋
And you, look at these pockets on your titties.
穿这件也没机会去法国
That shit ain't gonna get you to France.
谁能去法国？我要去法国
You know who's going to France? I'm going to France.
你说什么？
What you talking about?
好, 肩靠肩排成一排！快点！
All right, everybody line up, shoulder to shoulder! Move!
快点！
I said, move!
凶屁啊？   才第一天
What the hell? First day.
一开始就想混, 是吧？
So this is how we begin, huh?
你们总是在互相攻击
At each other's throats.
有两种方式可以争夺世界上最高建筑的排名
There's two ways to have the tallest building in the world.
一, 盖自己的摩天大楼越高越好
One, build yourself a giant-ass skyscraper.
二 ...
Two...
把别人的大楼给拆了
...tear all the other skyscrapers down.
我们要这里建立
We're here to build.
要建立一个团队
To build a team.
你早点想清楚
The quicker you get that through your heads,
就有更好的机会组成团队
the better chance you got of making that team.
【世界街舞大赛】是你们在世界上成名的机会
Battle of the Year is your chance to stand on top of the world.
再这样小鼻子小眼睛注定失败
But not if you keep thinking small.
别以为你比旁边的跳的好就够了
Not if you're just trying to prove you're better than the b-boy next to you.
嘿, 教练, 我用不着证明
Hey, Coach, I ain't got to prove shit.
我知道我比站在我旁边的更好
I know I'm better than the b-boy standing next to me.
闭上你的臭嘴!  来呀! 试看看啊!
Still running that mouth, bro? Want to try and shut it?
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
够了！
All right, that's it! That's it!
够了！你们两个有问题吗？
That's enough! You two got a problem?
敲敲他嫉妒山鸡
Do Knock's just jealous of Rooster. Hey!
闭嘴！
I said, shut it!
回去站好！
Get back in line!
排队！
Get in line!
你们想知道谁最好的, 是吧？
So you got to know which one's the best, huh?
好吧, 那就来尬一下
Well, let's clear the decks and find out.
分成两队, 两个队长
We're splitting into teams. I need two captains.
敲敲对山鸡, 真是意外啊...
Do Knock and Rooster, surprise, surprise.
挑选你的队员
Pick your teams.
双重麻烦
Double Trouble.
阿尼斯,  福利兹
Anis, Flipz.
千瓦
Kilowatt.
萨莫
Samo.
就是这样！开始！
That's it, that's it! Let's go!
先热热身
I want to see a warm-up.
哦！
Oh!
跳啊, 小个子！
Get it, little man!
让他见识见识！
Get him out of there!
宝贝！你在做什么？
Let's go, baby! What you doing, huh?
跳啊, 秀啊
Work it out, work it out.
教练, 我可以问你一个问题吗？
Coach, can I ask you a question?
整他, 山鸡！
Smoke him, Rooster!
如果目标是整合团队, 那......
If the idea is making these guys a team, then...
为什么让他们彼此斗舞？
Why have them battle? Yeah.
他们都被宠坏了
Isn't there enough bad blood already?
只是想弄清楚为什么我们要捅马蜂窝
Just trying to figure out why we're kicking the hornets' nest.
这些家伙不像没有感受到压力啊
It's not like these guys don't feel the pressure.
完全搞错方向
Wrong kind of pressure.
正确的导正才会让他们团结一心
The right kind will make them a team.
尬啊！
Let's go!
尬啊, 宝贝！
Let's go, baby!
让我来教教你们
I'm about to show you how it's done.
是啊, 这是正确的, 孩子
Yeah, that's right, boy. What?
兄弟, 你有事吗！
Man, you ain't got nothing!
尬他！
Yeah, get him!
是啊, 换他尬啦
Yeah, put it to him now.
呦, 骗子, 你在干什么？
Yo, Grifter, what are you doing?
呦, 还没轮到你
Yo, it's not even your turn.
怪胎
That's so wack.
♪ No one can requote this No one is the dopest
♪ Tell me if you smell me Tell me you never felt me
♪ Coming on to help me Not to overwhelm me
♪ Move your body
换我来啦
Back up. I got this.
换我 换我
I got this. I got this.
♪ Bring it, whatever Whatever the weather
♪ I never say never ♪
我尬过你了！    是哦！
I just owned you! Oh, yeah!
呀！  就这点本事吗？
Yeah! That's all you got, kid?
尤其是你, 山鸡！无庸置疑
And especially you, Rooster! No more questions.
无庸置疑...     你开我玩笑是吧?
No more questions. This is a joke, right?
我看起来像是在开玩笑？
I look like I'm joking?
黑色星期五, "骗子", 必须淘汰一个
Today's Friday, Grifter, somebody's got to go.
不是我 搞啥! 不是我... 教练, 应该是他们其中一个
Not me. Hell, no, not me, Coach. Any one of them, yo.
你选一个啊    就是你!
Take your damn pick. You are my pick.
我说我们分队尬舞
I said we're breaking into teams.
但你没有融入队友, 有吗？
But you didn't become part of a team, did you?
但我尬了他们, 教练!  我宰过......
Yeah, but I just roasted them, Coach. I smoked...
“我, 我, 我”你眼里只有"自我"
"I, I, I." Everything out of you is "I".
你甚至连团队作战的观念都没有？
You even understand the concept of a team?
团队作战是没有"自我"的...
Might be a cliche, son, but there is no "I" in team,
以后也不准有
and there'll be no "I" in this team.
又还不是个舞团, 这只是一个小分队！
This ain't no team, this is a crew!
很显然, 我比任何人都强！
And obviously, I'm better than anyone on it!
恭喜
Congratulations.
呦, 教练！
Yo, Coach!
教练！
Coach!
哟, 我比"敲敲"还棒
Yo, I've taken shits bigger than Do Knock.
Sisqo想去那边
Sisqo wannabe over there.
这是不对的... "骗子", 宰了他... 尬他!
It's not right. Grifter smoked him, roasted him.
太冷酷了, 宝贝
That was cold, babe.
教练使出杀鸡儆猴之术
Coach fired off a warning shot. Damn right.
不要让他找到把柄....
Don't give the man what he wants...
淘汰!
You will be gone.
恭喜你, "骗子" 你是最好的
Congratulations, Grifter. You're the best.
这里是你的公车票
Here's your bus pass.
淘汰!
You will be gone.
可惜淘汰的不是山鸡
Too bad it wasn't Rooster.
感谢上帝, 那不是我
Thank God it wasn't me.
是啊, 说的对极了
Yeah, word.
好多鞋,  是的
Lot of kicks. Oh, yeah.
我妹的老公的表哥的情妇帮Puma做广告
My sister's husband's cousin's mistress runs advertising for Puma,
所以她提供了一些给我们
so she hooked us up with some gear.
那两个家伙怎么解决？
Am I gonna have a problem with those two?
哪两个？  富兰克林
Those two? Catch up, Franklyn.
怎么处理山鸡和敲敲？
What's the deal with Rooster and Do Knock?
两个都在耍嘴皮子
They're in the middle of a really heated Twitter war
所以...   讲重点!
right now, so... The point?
他们就像Shaq去呛Kobe的事件
They're like Shaq and Kobe.
他们曾经是携手合作的战友
They used to be real tight, even ran a crew together.
发生了什么事？  你知道
So what happened? You've seen them.
各个都想当王
They both want to be the man.
说清楚点, 兄弟
Got to be more to it than that, man.
前阵子, 他们俩爱上同一个妞
A while back, they were both dating the same chick.
用膝盖想也知道
You know how that goes.
两个兄弟爱上同一个女孩,
Two guys fall in love with the same girl,
用跳舞对决
settle it with dance.
像古老童话故事那样...
It's a tale as old as...
...as time.
新的袋子？
We got new bags?
We got bags?
每人一个？
We all get one?
什么？
What?
呦！
Yo!
嘿！
Hey!
哟, 唐帝送的, 兄弟
Yo, listen up. This came from Dante, man.
你知道这要花多少钱？这些都不便宜
You know how much these cost? These aren't cheap.
我知道我买不起
I know I can't afford it.
什么？PS Vita！
What? No way. I got a PS Vita!
真的？可以从背面进行操作
Are you serious? You can control it from the back.
哟, 我得到了一个刮胡刀, 我需要这个
Yo, I got a shaver. Yo, I needed this.
叛徒, 你又没有长胡子
Rebel, you don't have facial hair.
嘿, 我用相机跟你换
Hey, I'll trade you my camera for that.
好多喔
It's got everything.
像是在过圣诞节...  真的假的
It's like Christmas in here right now, seriously.
评判的准则是...
The criteria's to judge on are
编舞, 主题, 音乐,
choreography itself, theme and music,
舞团跳舞的一致性
and if the crew are synchronized.
第一轮得进前四强
So the top four crews from the first rounds
才有资格晋级第二轮...
are qualified for the second round...
简单的说, 兄弟们
It's real simple, gentlemen.
要是进不了前四强
You don't place among the top four teams,
就没机会争冠了
you don't even get a chance to battle for the world championship.
六周以后, 有针对俄罗斯的对抗赛
In six weeks, we have an exhibition against Russia.
想赢就得整合成一个跳舞的团队
For us to have any chance, we must become a team.
一直提醒你们团队中没有自我
And since we've been reminded there's no "I" in team,
“我”现在被禁了
the word "I" is now forbidden.
字典里再也没有这个字眼
We will hereafter strike it from our vocabulary.
谁说了"我"这个字
Whenever the word "I" comes out of one of your mouths,
整个团队连座处分100下伏地挺身
the entire team will do 100 pushups.
不团结在一起就没有机会
You will become "we," or we don't stand a chance.
兄弟们, 听好了
All right, gentlemen, listen up.
我们先轻松的练习一下
We'll begin this nice and easy.
先开始同步练习... 了解吗？
All right, sync drills. Everybody clear?
五, 六, 七, 八！
And five, six, seven, eight!
注意到你旁边的家伙了没？
Feel the guy next to you?
【世界街舞大赛】时, 我们应该闭着眼睛都能跳
By the Battle of the Year, we should be able to do this blindfolded.
你害我搞乱了, 闭嘴!
You're messing me up, bro. Shut up, man.
我会宰了你
I'll smoke you.
你再讲, 我就要爆掉你的菊花
Keep talking, I'm gonna bust your ass.
我们好像听到了 "我"？
Did we hear "I" over here?
你知道该怎么做, 兄弟们
You know what to do, gentlemen.
一, 二...
One, two...
跳啊！跳啊！没时间了！
All right, let's go, let's go! Time is short here now!
保持队形
Keep that formation tight.
就是这样
There it is.
没错！
Right!
就是这样没错
That's what I'm talking about.
终于有点成效了
Now we're getting somewhere.
整好队形  我们再做一次
All right, form your lines up. Let's do it again.
教练, 我们刚才的动作, 像...
Coach, we just did it, like... Come on, man.
等一下
Hold on a second.
这是我们跳舞的奥林匹克运动会
This is the Olympics of our sport.
妈的疯了.... 叫什么叫,  阿斯达 ？
Shit is crazy. What's that, Abbstarr?
教练, 没有不敬, 但“霹雳舞”不是一种运动
Coach, no disrespect, but b-boying is not a sport.
是一个舞蹈艺术形式
It's a dance. What we do is an art form.
就是说嘛
Yeah, that's right.
嘿, 听好了
All right, hey, listen up.
你说的没错
That's right.
艺术与体育, 富有哲理的对话
Art versus sport, very philosophical conversation.
坐下来...  让我们来谈谈
Let's all have a seat. Let's talk about this.
你听说过的一个名叫魔术强森的家伙？
You ever hear of a guy named Magic Johnson?
当然, 当然
Of course, yeah. Of course.
当然听过
Of course you have.
打篮球是一种运动
Played basketball, a sport.
但是他打球的方式
But watching him play,
像是艺术、行云流畅的诗歌
it's like art, poetry in motion.
有哪里不搭嘎吗?
Why can't it be both?
整好队形, 重新练习
Let's form it up, and let's run it again.
我们可以训练一整晚
We'll be here all night if you want to be!
现在, 跳吧！
Now, run it!
没错就是这样  跳啊!
That's what I'm talking about. That's it.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
继续跑, 兄弟们, 还有四圈！
Keep going, guys, four more!
你们在干什么？难道你不是应该
What is this? Aren't you supposed to be
盯着他们跳舞吗？  我们是啊
working on the routine? We are.
我看倒像是犯人被罚集体跑操场？
By running them like a chain gang?
"骗子" 他人呢？
Where's Grifter?
他走了
He's gone.
去哪儿了？  淘汰了
Gone where? Cut him.
所以, 你把我们最好的霹雳舞者给淘汰了？
So you cut one of our best b-boys?
应该说... 他曾经是最好的
Actually, he was the best.
我想确认一下... 我们的想法是否还一致
Let me just make sure we're on the same page here.
我没搞错吧, 还是它不是你出的主意
Am I mistaken, or was it not your idea
带美国最好的霹雳舞者去参加世界杯？
to take America's best b-boys to the worlds?
你错了
You're mistaken.
我打的主意是, 组最好的舞团去参加大赛
It was my idea to bring the best team to the worlds,
这是我们正在做的
which is what we're doing.
哪里有"我们"?
Ain't no "we," all right?
你是我花钱请来的...    你别管!
You work for me.  Back off.
不, 你才别乱搞!  赞助舞团的人是我
No, you back off. I'm sponsoring this team.
我不顾一切的挺你
I stuck my neck out for you.
我打电话给你, 你都不回
I've been calling you, you don't call me back,
所以我就来这儿看看是怎么回事,
so I got to come down here to see what's going on,
你却只会叫他们跑操场！
and you're running my boys into the ground!
还有, 你在摆烂
Meanwhile, you're a mess.
满身酒气冲天
You smell like you're sweating gin.
你还吐在鞋子上？
And is that vomit on your shoes?
鞋子是富兰克林的
Shoes are Franklyn's.
惨了
That's not cool.
我没时间跟你再鬼扯下去
I don't got time for this.
我要去忙俄罗斯对抗赛
I got to get your team ready for the Russian exhibition.
下来
Get your ass down here.
他是怎么操练他们的
How hard's he working these guys?
很严格
Real hard.
但是有效
But it's working.
他疯了, 但他知道自己在做什么
WB might be crazy, D, but he knows what he's doing.
让他们团结
He's bringing them together.
他怎么弄的?
And how is that?
敌人的敌人
The enemy of my enemy
就是我的朋友
is my friend.
叫他们集合
Get them inside.
感觉如何, 教练？
How you feeling, Coach?
很好
Fine. Yeah?
刚刚你看起来像一只羚羊
You look like a gazelle out there.
有关节炎的羚羊
A gazelle with arthritis.
我只是想问问你请人来编舞的事
I just wanted to ask you about the choreographer thing again.
周五就要跟俄国人比赛了
We got the Russians in five weeks.
是啊...呃...
Yeah... Uh...
你帮我找
Get me the best.
遵命
Got it.
还有别的事吗, 富兰克林？
Anything else, Franklyn? Yeah.
是啊, 我只是想谢谢你
Yeah, I just wanted to thank you.
为了什么？
For what?
所有的事
For everything.
D曾说跟着你可以学到更多, 他是对的
D said I could learn a lot from you, and he was right.
他很聪明
He can be a wise man.
是啊
Yeah.
我们念高中时
We were just in high school and everything,
大家都很疯
but being here is definitely, like, mad emotional.
当你在走廊走着, 就好像,
When you walk through the hallways, it's like,
碰到的人就是竞争对手
that competitor, that's the guy
当场就尬起来, 你听的懂吗？
you're competing against right there, you know what I mean?
不要慢下来！
That's it. Don't slow it down!
慢了！跟上！
You're slowing down! Pick it up!
跟上！
Come on!
俄罗斯排名前九已经很强
Russia's Top 9 has experience on their side.
组团超过10年
They've been a team for over 10 years.
他们是2010年【世界街舞大赛】 冠军
They were Battle of the Year champions in 2010,
艺术性、舞技和表演能力都是一流的
known for their artistry, finesse and showmanship.
再来！
Now, run it! Do it again!
...跳舞, 兄弟们, 这是关于
...dancing, fellas, it's about
融合为一, 对吧？   没问题
becoming one, right? Should be fine.
刚开始生疏, 慢慢会越来越熟练
He's a little brusque at first, but you'll get used to it.
安静
Settle down.
就是他
Here he comes.
她是谁？
Who's she?
编舞的
Choreographer.
她是个女的
She's a girl.
是啊   女的
Indeed she is, yeah.
找她来有用吗？
She's gonna help us win Battle of the Year? Yeah.
霹雳舞女孩？是的
A b-girl? Yeah.
街舞大赛时由她负责编导
She's gonna help us flip the script at the Battle of the Year.
她来了   不要再讲悄悄话了
She's coming. We can't whisper anymore.
史黛西    很高兴认识你
Stacy. It's nice to meet you.
布雷克  你好
Blake. Nice to meet you.
富兰克林说你是一个舞者
So, Franklyn here tells me you're a dancer.
编舞
Choreographer.
对
Right.
那个...  史黛西
Look... Stacy,
丑话说在前头
I'm just gonna be honest with you here.
我怕在这种情况下, 这些男孩,
I'm afraid in this situation, with the boys,
你可能有点...
you might be a bit of a...
为我们开启新的诗章
An exciting new chapter.
会让人分心
A distraction.
会分心      谢谢
A distraction. Thank you.
他们需要加强专注力和纪律
Well, maybe we need to teach them a little bit of focus and discipline.
相信我, 你需要我
Trust me, you need me.
丑媳妇要见公婆
Let's meet the boys.
我是史黛西, 你们的编舞老师
My name is Stacy, and I'm gonna be your choreographer.
无论你想, 你可以教教我
You can teach me whatever you want.
最好躺在地板上！
Preferably on the floor!
你会按摩吗？
Are you good with massages, too?
大腿内侧那边很需要
'Cause I have a lot of tension right here up in my upper thigh region.
说够了吗？
Are you done?
让我来解释一下
Let me explain something to you.
我对小鬼没兴趣
I'm not into boys.
嘿, 我喜欢这一点   这很酷
Hey, I like that. That's cool.
我并不介意
I'm cool with that. I don't mind.
我喜欢成熟的男人
I'm into men.
所以, 你和我, 下辈子吧
So you and I, we won't have a problem.
像这样   这很酷
Like that. That's cool.
第一件事, 明天早上几点？
First thing tomorrow morning?
六点
6:00.
从头来, 五, 六, 七, 八
From the top, clean, five, six, seven, eight.
一, 二, 三, 四......
One, two, three, four...
你们是跳霹雳舞的,  跳啊！
Y'all are supposed to be b-boys. Come on, let's go!
千瓦, 你搞屁啊
Kilowatt, you're killing me.
一, 二, 三, 四......
One, two, three, four...
停停停！
All right, hold up, hold up!
大家停止
Everybody stop.
你在干嘛, "敲敲"？
The hell are you doing, Do Knock?
我做了什么？ “我” ？
What did I do? "I"?
又来了？
Again?
受罚, 兄弟！白痴
Come on, man! Idiot. Who's stupid now?
你再讲, 混蛋, 我会打你屁股
Keep talking, bitch, I'll beat your ass.
打败我吗？你总是活在我阴影之下, 这是有原因的,
Beat me? There's a reason why you're always in my shadow,
难怪萝莉会甩掉你
and that's the same reason Lauren left your punk ass.
起来！
Get your ass up!
怎样？
What?
你这个矮骡子
Yeah, that's right. You was half the man I was.
哟, 哟
Yo, yo
你不管吗？
You're not gonna stop this?
嘿, 嘿！
Hey, hey!
够了！拉开他！
That's enough! Get him back!
退下！ 退下！
Back up! Back up!
够了！
That's it!
又是女的吗？
This about that girl?
那女的现在跟谁啊？
Either one of you still with her?
没有
Huh? No.
开天窗说亮话
So let me get this straight.
我们曾经是朋友, 现在反目成仇
We used to be friends, now we're swapping blows over
女人都跟别人跑了
some girl we're both glad is gone
早就变成别人的小三了
and who no doubt has hooked up with some other fool.
没说错吧
That about right?
想清楚
Let me be crystal clear.
好汉不提当年勇
History is exactly that. History!
结束！你明白了吗？
Fighting ends now! You understand me?
是的, 教练
Yes, Coach.
谁还想斗, 就淘汰！
Any one of you even think about fighting, you will be gone!
荒唐！浪费时间！
This is ridiculous! We're running out of time!
整队！ 继续练!
Now, line up and let's run it!
♪ Hold your flix I'm not for the photo op's
♪ It's Black, code name Yaphet Kotto ock
♪ My twist like a ratchet in an auto shop
♪ Since granddaddy old Desoto stopped and he got the Caddie
♪ I been gladly serving any y'all cats wanna act determined
♪ Spit pesticides for rats and vermin
♪ Seem like none of y'all chumps is learning
♪ Party people gather round
♪ What we have here is a brand new sound
♪ Reach for my waist you hit the ground
♪ You better duck when that awful sound goes
♪ Boom
♪ That's what's happening in the parking lot
♪ That's what's happening on stage
♪ The man at hand that rule the school
♪ And reach and teach the blind and find a way from A to Z
♪ And be the most to boast I'm load and proud
♪ The game and reign that remain
♪ The heat is on so feel the fire come off the empire
♪ Or the more higher level of depth one step beyond dope
♪ To suckers all scope and hope to cope but nope
♪ 'Cause I could never let 'em on top of me
♪ I play 'em out like a game of Monopoly
♪ Let it speed around the board like an astro
♪ And send them to jail for trying to pass go
♪ Party people gather round
♪ What we have here is a brand new sound
♪ Reach for my waist you hit the ground
♪ You better duck when that awful sound goes
♪ Boom
♪ That's what's happening in the parking lot
♪ That's what's happening on stage ♪
哟, 你跳舞的艺名从哪来的, 花美男？
Yo, where'd you get your b-boy name from, Lil Adonis?
在这里
Here.
那是什么？  我妈给的
What's that? That's my mom.
15岁时我第一次跳舞比赛
First time I tried a battle, I'm 15.
我的母亲, 她知道我与众不同
But my mother, see, she knows I'm not like the other kids.
我很害怕   我是同志
I'm scared. I'm gay.
是啊, 他是个妈宝
Yeah, he's a mama's boy.
你可以说我
Say all you want about me,
但别提到我妈一个字...
but say one more word about my mother...
还好吧？
We all good in here?
没事  教练
Yeah, we good, Coach.
花美男？
Lil Adonis?
你呢？
We all good?
没事, 教练
Good, Coach.
兄弟, 淘汰越来越严格了
Man, these cuts are getting crazy.
不坏
Not bad.
放下你的自我
You need to let go of your ego.
手表坏了吗, 叛徒？
Something wrong with your watch, Rebel?
呃...不, 教练, 没坏
Uh... No, Coach, it's good.
那我们干嘛等这么久？
Then what was so important to make the rest of us wait?
俄罗斯比赛不到两周的时间
We battle Russia's top crew in less than two weeks.
不想说耶
We'd rather not say.
理由?
I said, why were we late?
还是不要说的好
We'd really rather not say.
讲啊
I said, why were we late?
刚刚在大便
We had to take a shit.
越来越难挑了, 是吧？
Getting harder to pick them, huh?
天哪, 大家跳的越来越一致
God, each one of these guys has the moves down.
不是动作的问题, 富兰克林
It isn't about the moves anymore, Franklyn.
是关于化学变化
It's about chemistry.
是指越来越团结吗？
Like which dudes are getting along?
不是
Not about that, either.
有名的舞团不见得大家都相处融洽
Record books are filled with teams that never got along,
冠军舞团也一样
championship teams, too.
你想说什么
So, what, then?
要有亮点
Those teams had something else.
有冲撞才有进步
The players pushed each other to greatness.
告诉"难搞的" 我找他
Tell Intricate I need to see him.
是
Okay.
明天就是我们等待的一天
All right, gentlemen, tomorrow's the day we've been waiting for.
俄罗斯队纪律高、同步、精准
The Russians are disciplined, synchronized, precise.
记住, 要赢得这场唯一的办法, 就是发挥团队精神
Remember, the only way to win this is going there as a team.
去睡吧!  明天是大日子
Get some sleep. Tomorrow's the big day.
今晚比赛的特点
Tonight's battle features
俄罗斯的前9尬美国梦幻队！
Russia's Top 9 versus America's Dream Team!
跳吧！跳吧！
Let's go! Come on!
叛徒上场！
Let's get 'em, Rebel!
叛徒! 加油!
Come on, Rebel.
"童童"！加油！
Let's go, Kid! Come on!
啪
Pow!
这是什么狗屁？
Come on. What is this shit?
他妈的！
God damn it!
上啊! 跳啊!
Go, go, go. Come on. Chief, chief, go, go.
上！
All right, let's go!
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
你的团队在哪里？
Where's your team?
山鸡, 归队！
Rooster, get out there!
团队！团队！
Act like a team!
该死的！
Damn it!
你的团队在哪里？
Where's your team?
回来啦！
Get off the floor! Get off the floor!
你看你做了什么？
You see what you did?
叫他们通通到外面去！
Get 'em outside right now!
哦, 该死
Oh, shit.
布雷克！
Blake!
跟他们谈谈吧？
Are you gonna talk to them?
没什么好说的
I got nothing to say to them I haven't already said.
回程路上教练居然气到连一句话都没说
Can't believe Coach didn't say a word to us the whole way back.
就是你搞砸的
It's 'cause you blew it.
什么？你的错
What? All of y'all blew it.
单挑就能代表梦幻队？我看是梦幻女
Call yourself the Dream Team? More like the Dreamgirls.
你怪我？是啊, 我是认真的！
Look, are you serious? Yeah, I'm serious!
阿尼斯, 告诉他们！谁的错
Anis, tell 'em! Back me up!
这是你的错, 山鸡
It was your fault, Rooster.
你说什么？
What'd you say?
你听见了! 就是因为你才输的
You heard me! We lost tonight because of you, man!
我的错? 我跳出来拯救大家... 我哪有错!
Because of me? If anything, I tried to rescue everybody! Yo, I'm over this!
听到我耳朵都长茧了！
I've heard that same tired shit for years!
老是怪罪别人！
Anything happens, it's always somebody else's fault!
哟, 你怪我干嘛？
Yo, why you coming at me like this?
我的脚受伤了, 我累了, 就是你的错, 兄弟！
'Cause my feet hurt, I'm tired, and it's your fault, man!
呦, 你有问题吗？连你的人都这么说了, 山鸡
Yo, what the hell is your problem? Listen to your boy, Rooster.
不, 你也闭嘴！你也是烂货！
No, you shut up, too! You're as bad as him!
怎样, 你想对抗全世界吗  法国佬？
What, you against the whole world now, Frenchie?
没有, 就你们两个混蛋！
No, just you two assholes!
自从我加入舞团,
Ever since I walked in these doors,
我为舞团付出一切！
I gave everything I got in this team!
所有的一切！
Everything!
教练是对的, 这支舞团不是没有机会
But Coach was right, this team isn't going nowhere
如果任你们继续分裂恶搞
if you two don't get together right now!
看看你的周围！
Look around you!
看看这些队友！
Look at these guys!
我们明明拥有获胜的条件！
We got everything we need to win, right here!
成为最棒的舞团
To be the best there is!
而你们就是他妈的乱搞
And you're too goddamn ignorant to see that!
你需要管管你的人！    闭嘴！
You need to check your boy! Shut up!
你和山鸡, 可能还有其他机会
Guys like you and Rooster, you might get other chances,
对我而言, 就只有这里
but for someone like me, this shit is it, man.
错过这舞团我就再也没有机会了, 永远！
I'm never gonna get another shot at this, ever!
所以 我一直忍着
So I'm taking it,
我想我该揍你或是教训我的老友！
even if I gotta punch you in the face or dog my oldest friend!
兄弟, 这舞团是我生命中最重要的！
I want this, man, more than anything in my life!
问题是, 你们这两个混蛋到底想干嘛？
Question is what the hell do you two assholes want?
♪ Independent now Sans label
山鸡！山鸡！
Rooster! Rooster!
♪ Haters gonna ruin it ♪
我们谈谈
We need to talk.
- 少啰嗦   - 滚开
- There's been too much talk already. - Move.
你干嘛这么欠揍？
Why you gotta be such an asshole?
你想打架吗？烦死我了！
You want to fight? I'm tired of your shit!
你的兄弟说的没错
I'm trying to tell you your boy is right.
是啊, 我知道, 我是一混蛋啊  怎样
Yeah, I know, I'm an ass. I got it.
我也老是怪东怪西的, 跟你一样
No, I'm as much to blame as you are.
你知道你是多么有才华？
Do you know how talented you are?
你随便跳一跳就会了
You try a move once, bam, you get that shit.
我呢？我必须靠不断的练习才跟的上你
Me? I got to practice and practice my ass off just to come close to you!
我一直很嫉妒
I've always been jealous of that.
但是, 这就样我才能站在这里
But that's what got me here.
你逼我成长
You got me here.
让我有机会加入舞团
Without that, I don't even make this team.
哟, 你到底想怎样, 兄弟？
Yo, where you going with this, man?
我要赢！
I want to win!
我要赢
I want to win.
抛开过去, 我们就能赢
We put aside all our old bullshit, we can win this.
他们需要我们
They need us.
萝莉怎么办？
What about Lauren?
我们分手两个月后, 你们才在一起的
I broke that off two months before you guys even hooked up.
真的假的?
Really? Really.
那你一直在跟我吵个屁？
So why you been acting all crazy?
因为你太容易动怒了
'Cause it pisses you off!
不过 我想尽释前嫌
But I want to squash this right now.
来吧
Come on.
让我们重新开始
Let's be partners again.
放音乐
Just play my music, man.
抱一下
Hey, give me a hug, bro.
抱抱吗
A hug? Yeah!
给我一个拥抱
Give me a hug.
兄弟好样的
Come on, man. All right.
教练！
Coach!
呦, 教练！醒醒吧, 你迟到了
Yo, Coach! Wake up, man. You're late.
都过六点了, 我们该开始训练
It's after 6:00, we gotta train right now.
滚出去  今天放假
Get out. There's no practice today.
起床啦!     滚出我的房间！
Come on. Get up, man. Get out of my damn room!
我们哪里都不去
We aren't going anywhere.
“我们”你懂个屁
"We." You don't know shit about "we," son.
我们懂... 我们搞砸了
We get it. We screwed up.
来啦, 叫叫叫个屁
Come on, let's go. You don't tell me shit.
我们不是叫你该怎么做, 教练
We're not telling you what to do, Coach.
我们在求你
We're asking.
教练, 请
Come on, Coach, please.
来啦, 大哥
Come on, man.
训练室,  10分钟后
Training room, 10 minutes.
看吧
Told you.
我们想赢, 我们就要改变我们的态度
We want to win, we need to change how we think.
听起来很熟悉？成功是一种选择
Sound familiar? Success is a choice.
真正的冠军都知道, 心里想的才是关键
Every true champion knows mental game is the key.
最大的动力来源
It's our greatest power.
普通人不懂的驾驭他, 甚至于根本不知道
Most people never touch that power. Don't even know they have it.
不断地重蹈覆辙
Go around, doing the same old shit,
冥顽不化
thinking the same old thoughts every damn day.
混吃等死
It's why those people will tell you, "Same shit, different day."
宇宙中唯一不变的真理就是, 什么都会变
Truth is the only thing permanent in this universe is change.
与其抱怨这些训练
Instead of griping about these drills,
不如说,  “训练可以带给我们舞团,
choose to say, "We're giving these drills, our team,
“我们国家, 我们个人”
"our country, every ounce of ourselves. "
冠军之路
Choose to see ourselves as champions.
走路, 说话, 吃, 喝, 思考就像个冠军样
Walk, talk, eat, drink, think like champions,
没人可以阻挡我们
we become unstoppable.
魔鬼藏在细节里
We become champions in everything we do.
我看到你们的进步
All right, it's looking good. I can see progress.
我知道你累了
Holy... I know you're tired,
才过45分钟而已, 别像个娘们  深呼吸
but it's the fourth quarter, gentlemen. Suck it up. Deep breath.
再来
Let's run it again.
明天是星期五
Tomorrow's Friday.
还要淘汰一个
Last man standing.
淘汰不是重点
Can't think of it as cutting the last man.
要这样想... 舞团终于要成军了!
Gotta think of it as choosing our final team.
是吗？
Yeah?
成军后会比较轻松吗？
Does that make it any easier?
不会
No, not really.
嘿, 教练
Hey, Coach.
- 嘿    - 嘿, 宝贝
- Hey. - Hey, baby.
好吧, 再见
All right, see ya. See ya.
你真蠢？
Are you really this stupid?
教练, 我...         规则很简单
Coach, look... The rules are very simple.
请进
Come in.
没关系, 宝贝, 爸爸在这里
It's okay, baby, Daddy's here.
她叫阿丽娜
This is Aleena.
没关系, 宝贝...   妈妈很快就回来
It's okay, baby. Mama's gonna be back soon.
她好漂亮         谢谢
She's beautiful. Thank you.
没事
It's okay.
你有听过 4个撇步？
You ever hear of the Four S's?
那是什么？   婴儿包巾、侧抱、摇摇、嘘嘘
What's that? Swaddle, side, shimmy, shush.
我做给你看
May I?
没关系, 宝贝
It's okay, baby.
瞧, 包巾很舒服
See, swaddling soothes them.
有点紧, 但不要太紧
Tight, but not too tight.
然后, 侧抱
Then you turn her on her side like this.
摇一摇
Then you shimmy back and forth.
不行吧
It's not gonna work.
行!   你不要吵
It will, quiet.
嘘嘘
Shushing.
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
我的儿子有腹绞痛问题
My boy had colic when he was a baby.
你有儿子？
You got a boy?
没问题了
It's okay.
等我一下
I'll be right back.
说吧
Start talking.
我不能把她们丢在纽约不顾
I'm not gonna leave my family back in New York, Coach.
在过去的三个月里, 只能靠信用卡过活
For the last three months, we've been living off credit cards.
你已经溜出了三个月？
You been sneaking out for the last three months?
不是每晚, 有机会的话
It's not every night. It's when I can.
不要淘汰我, 教练
You can't kick me out, Coach.
拜托, 不要在这个时候
Please, not now.
应该有更好的办法
There are better ways to handle this.
我家没钱, 教练
I don't come from much, Coach.
我只能靠跳舞
All I got is breaking.
你应该优先照顾你的家人
You gotta take care of your family first.
我有在做啊, 教练
That's what I'm trying to do, Coach.
难道你不明白吗？舞团是我的机会
Don't you see? This team is my chance
能给阿丽娜更好的未来
to give Aleena chances I never had.
有机会给她更好的生活
Chances to know that we can actually do something
只要赢得【世界街舞大赛】
with our lives if I make it to Battle of the Year.
明天就只剩下13名正式团员了
Team goes down to the final 13 tomorrow.
如果我不够资格进前13名, 就淘汰我
If I don't make top 13, send me home.
我只是希望得到公平待遇
I just want my fair shake, Coach.
请不要现在就淘汰我
Please don't bus-pass me.
不要给我迟到
Don't be late.
唐帝要给你的
Delivery. From Dante.
“去法国前, 烧掉那丑死的连帽运动服 ”
"For France. Burn that goddamn hoodie."
我的运动服有什么问题？   没有
What's wrong with my hoodie? Nothing.
无业游民风格
It's just very "vagrant chic."
很好
It's nice.
审判日
Judgment Day.
嗯
Yeah.
你会选择谁？
Who you gonna pick?
不是我
I'm not.
你来选
You are.
我？  你来
Me? You.
其实我已经挑好人选了
I know which man I'd send home.
名字先写下来了
Wrote his name on the back.
让我看看是谁
Great. Let me see. I'll go get him.
教练要知道, 当他的判断有偏差时
Coach has gotta know when his own judgment's biased.
就是怕感性大于理智
I can't help feeling my heart's talking louder than my head.
兄弟们都很努力
Guys have worked too hard.
撑到现在
Come too far.
所以, 我相信你的判断, 富兰克林
So I'm trusting your judgment, Franklyn.
你跟我一样了解他们
You know them as well as I do.
不, 我不能选择
No, I can't choose.
淘汰一个
Take one down.
如果我选错了人？
What if I pick the wrong guy?
你不会的
You won't.
好吧
Okay.
这不是淘汰最后一人
It's not like we're cutting the last man,
而是终于要组成舞团了
we're just picking the final team.
你说得对, 不会更轻松
You're right, doesn't make it any easier.
同一个
Same man.
哦, 富兰克林...
Oh, Franklyn...
你有资格了
You've earned it.
谢谢你, 教练
Thank you, Coach.
谢谢你, 富兰克林
Thank you, Franklyn.
哟, 巴比诺
Yo, Bambino.
虽然安慰不了你, 但这是教练最难的选择
I know this is no consolation, but this was the toughest choice for Coach.
我们到了法国会打电话给你
We'll give you a call when we get to France, won't we, guys?
最好是
Yeah. You better.
烂透了
That sucked.
嘿, 靠过来！
Hey, gentlemen! Huddle up!
靠过来
Let's huddle up!
听好了
All right, listen up.
我们要给唐帝做行前验收
We have our final presentation with Dante,
回宿舍换衣服, 一小时后见
so go back to your dorms, get changed, meet me back here in an hour.
哦, 带护照
Oh, and get your passports together.
我们要去法国！
Looks like we're going to France!
唐帝来了, 再彩排一下
Dante's at the gate, so let's run the intro one more time.
回到最初的队形, 整齐划一
Get in the first formation. Make sure it's clean.
预备 开始
Here we go.
棒极了
All right. It's looking great.
嘿,  WB , 有人想来道别
Hey, WB, somebody wants to wish us farewell
去法国之前
when we go to France.
WB 瞧瞧你
Look at WB.
WB , 现在是怎样, 宝贝？
WB, what's poppin', baby?
难以置信！
Unbelievable!
还好吗？
How you doing?
你呦, 卡迈勒！
Look at you. Yo, Kamel!
大哥, 哎, 我从小就是你的忠实粉丝
Man, hey, I been a big fan of yours since I was about this big.
你认识我吗？   什么？
You know me? What?
你是霹雳舞界的麦可乔丹耶
You're like the Michael Jordan of b-boys.
嘿, 见见我的好友
Hey, meet my friend.
嘿, 阿尼斯,
Hey, Anis, come here, look.
幸会
Honored, man.
哟, 你好!     我是"狙击手" 你好
Yo, what's good? Sniper. What's up, man?
呦！
Yo!
哟, 跳新的舞步给他们看
Yo, let's show them the new move.
现在吗？
Now?
来啦  跳啦
Yeah, come on, let's do it.
哟, 教练, 照过来！
Hey, yo, Coach, check this out!
五, 六, 七, 八......
Five, six, seven, eight...
山鸡！
Rooster!
哦, 不
Oh, no.
该死的
Damn.
靠
Shit.
兄弟们, 不要看我可怜
Come on, guys, don't watch me pack.
兄弟们, 我向来都是很自大
Guys, ever since I was about this big, it's always been about me.
山鸡唱独脚戏
The Rooster Show.
但是和你们相处这三个月以来
But these last three months with you guys,
与你们能成为兄弟...
being able to become brothers with you guys...
我只想说
I just gotta say
又是我的问题
it still is about me.
我实在没资格做队长
As a matter of fact, I shouldn't even be in this position.
敲敲, 你才有资格
Do Knock, it should be you.
哦, 谢谢你喔
Oh, for real?
阿尼斯, 到法国赢了就打电话给我, 好吗？
Anis, make sure you call me, in France, when y'all win, all right?
好
Will do, man.
告诉巴比诺他欠我人情
And tell Bambino he owes me.
嘿, 兄弟们......
Hey, guys...
跳的像个冠军, 我们就是冠军
Act like champions, be champions.
跟我一起念！
Come on, say it!
跳的像个冠军, 我们就是冠军
Act like champions, be champions.
兄弟们, 再会了
All right, guys, I'll see y'all later.
再见了, 兄弟
Later, dude. Peace, bro.
平安, 兄弟
Peace, dude.
一路顺风, 兄弟
Be safe, man.
谢谢你, 教练
Thanks, Coach.
我的荣幸, 山鸡
Been an honor, Rooster.
我们要去参加世界街舞大赛
We are going to Battle of the Year to take it.
拿金牌回美国！
Bringin' it back to the US!
美国！
US!
♪ Got your rhymes going round in my head
♪ So dance, little DJ, come on
♪ What's your name♪
♪ Hey, rollover DJ
♪ You're spinning away All my time
梦幻队, 宝贝
Dream Team, baby.
♪ Hey, who cares what you play
♪ Say whatever you say 'cause I don't mind
法国！
France!
几点了？ 好戏上场！
What time is it? Show time!
♪ Hey, rollover DJ
♪ You're spinning away All my time
♪ Hey, who cares what you play
♪ Say whatever you say 'cause I don't mind ♪
哇  真棒
Wow. Awesome.
这边, 布雷克
Come over here, Blake.
让我来给你介绍"托马斯"
Let me introduce you to Thomas Hergenrother,
【世界街舞大赛】的创始人
founder of Battle of the Year.
欢迎来到【世界街舞大赛】选手村
Welcome to the Battle of the Year Village.
谢谢你, 托马斯   很高兴能来到这里
Thank you, Thomas. Glad to be here.
很帅, 兄弟
Looking sharp, brother.
老朋友送我的
Gift from an old friend.
进去吧
Let's get inside.
哇
Damn.
接下来的几天里, 有很多事要做
So, over the next few days, there's much to do.
时间紧迫
Time is really tight,
超过20个舞团来自世界各地
and we have more than 20 crews coming from all over the world.
谢谢, 托马斯
All right, Thomas.
享受一下     非常感谢
Enjoy your stay. Thank you very much.
不客气
All right.
呦, 兄弟们, 德国人
Yo, guys, peep at the Germans.
法国佬在那边
French over there.
还有韩国仔
There's the Koreans.
看看他们
Look at them.
没有人认为我们能挤进前四名
No one thinks we've got a shot at top four.
他们干嘛不采访我们？
Why are they looking at us like that?
我们是美国人, 他们瞧不起我们
We're Americans, so, automatically, we're the assholes.
该死的, 兄弟, 这是怎么回事？
Damn, dude, what's up with that?
盛气凌人
That is what you have when you're the best.
放轻松     把行李拿进去
Just relax. Go put your stuff away,
观光一下, 快乐点
see the sights, have some fun.
♪ Sun is shining in the sky
♪ There ain't a cloud in sight
♪ It's stopped raining Everybody's in a play
♪ And don't you know It's a beautiful new day Hey, hey
♪ Yeah! ? Mr. Blue Sky
♪ Please tell us why
♪ You had to hide away for so long So long
♪ Where did we go wrong? ♪
哟, 这是我们想进去的, 兄弟们！
Yo, this is where we want to be, fellas!
请记住, 宵禁时间到10:00
And remember, we got curfew at 10:00.
该死的！唐！
Damn! Dang!
"福利兹"和"敲敲"抢头阵？
Flipz and Do Knock got that first set down?
是
Yes.
还要转换步伐...
Still need to work on that transition...
布雷克, 他们可以
Blake, they got it.
先停一下, 不要再烦恼比赛了
Don't you ever just stop thinking about the battle?
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系     只是...
It's okay. It's just...
环顾四周
Look around.
我们人在法国
We are in France
辛苦了半天才来到这里
and you worked your ass off to get us here.
放松一下  释放一下压力
So relax and quit stressing me out.
敬一下【世界街舞大赛】
To Battle of the Year.
敬法国
To France.
欢迎参加世界街舞大赛的开幕派对
Welcome to our big opening party of the Battle of the Year!
今年已经是第22届了
The Battle of the Year is already in its 22nd year.
别忘了, 不是来这边拼个输赢而已
Don't forget, it's not all about winning or losing.
大家群聚一堂, 庆祝嘻哈文化
The whole world is coming together to celebrate hip-hop culture.
呦, "混乱"   - 我要去洗手间
Yo, Mayhem. I'm-a go to the bathroom.
马上回来, 兄弟
I'll be right back. All right, man.
他很可爱     不管是来自哪个国家
He's cute. He's cute. So, no matter what
或者什么宗教, 让我们一起庆祝,
country you're from or what religion, let's celebrate,
同一个世界, 同一首歌
All Around the World, Same Song.
干杯, 山姆男孩！
To us, Sam boy!
我去拿饮料   小心
I'm gonna get a drink. Watch out.
好吧！
All right!
对不起        对不起
Excuse me. Excuse me.
妈的！
Shit!
喂! 你打翻了我的酒！对不起
Man, you just spilled my drink! I'm sorry.
对不起有个屁用？
I don't care if you're sorry, all right?
对不起    对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
哇, 哇！冷静!  他喝醉了
Whoa, whoa! You good? He's drunk.
没事啦  好啦~  好个屁!
Are you good right now? No, it's not good, all right?
这个混蛋刚刚打翻了我的酒
This asshole just came and spilled my drink.
好吧, 我赔你一杯
Okay, I'm gonna get you another one.
我不用你赔
I don't care if you get me another one.
我跟我的朋友坐在一起...    他们是你的朋友吗？
I was sitting with my friends... These your friends?
我请你们, 没事啦
Drinks on me, everything's cool.
开干了！上！
Fight, fight, fight! Let's go, go, go!
嘿！冷静下来！冷静下来！
Hey, hey, hey! Chill! Chill!
喂
Yeah.
什么？
What?
好, 托马斯
All right, Thomas.
我会处理
I'll handle it.
该死的！
Damn it!
才第一个晚上！
One night!
我让你们这些小鬼乐个一晚, 你们就这样报答我
I give you clowns one night, and you throw it back in my face.
教练, 请让我...         闭嘴
Coach, please let me... Shut up.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this shit.
果然出了洋相, 丑陋的美国人
You gave them exactly what they expected, ugly Americans.
你都不听我解释...
Come on, Coach, you didn't even let me explain what happen...
我说闭嘴
I said shut up.
你什么也没学到
You've learned nothing.
什么都没有
Nothing.
狗改不了吃屎
You're the exact same guys
跟三个月前一样
that walked through my door three months ago.
就是你
And you,
祸由你起
you started this little dance party.
喜欢打人是吧？
You like to hit people? Huh?
打我啊？
Want to take a swing at me?
不, 老兄咦？
No, man. Huh?
WB , 你在做什么？你在做什么？
WB, what are you doing? What are you doing?
托马斯说
Thomas called.
"狙击手"被取消资格
Sniper's been disqualified.
你明天滚回家    什么？
You go home tomorrow. What?
如果"狙击手"走了,  我也不干了
If Sniper's gone, I'm gone.
你威胁我   我没有
Don't you test me. I'm not.
哟, 如果"狙击手"走了, 我也走
Yo, if Sniper's going, I'm going.
我也一样, 教练
Me, too, Coach.
对不起, 教练, 没错
Sorry, Coach, that's right.
他走了, 大家都不跳了
He goes, we all go.
怎么回事
Start talking.
是当地的小混混起的头
These local punks were trying to start shit.
他们出拳打"花美男"
All right? They punked Lil Adonis.
这就是为什么"狙击手"也跳出来
That's why Sniper stepped up.
听我说
But listen.
几个月前, 他们两个就连用餐
A few months ago, Sniper couldn't even sit
都不能坐在一起
at the same table as Adonis.
互看不顺眼
He couldn't even look at him,
现在竟然为他挺身而出
and now he's fighting for him.
教练你要怎么骂都行
Say what you want, Coach, but down to a man,
他们已经是今非昔比
these are not the same guys that walked through your door that first day.
你想要组一个团队
You wanted a team.
他们就是
Well, you got one.
我跟托马斯谈一谈
I gotta call Thomas.
如何？
So, what now?
我们等待
We wait.
兄弟们！兄弟们
Guys! Guys.
你跟托马斯谈过了？
Did you talk to Thomas?
嗯
Yeah.
结果呢？
And?
"狙击手"
Sniper.
有, 长官
Yes, sir.
你可以留下
You're staying.
听好了
Listen up.
这是一个漫长的夜晚
It's been a long night.
睡个好觉
Get some sleep.
明天是大日子
Big day tomorrow.
兄弟们...
Gentlemen...
团队的感觉如何呀？
How's it feel to be a team?
超赞, 教练
Damn good, Coach.
我是Artem Korolev,
My name is Artem Korolev,
我为MTV俄罗斯作实况报导
and I am reporting live for MTV Russia,
【世界街舞大赛】, 在法国蒙彼利埃
from Battle of the Year, here in Montpellier, France.
上千名嘻哈迷涌入现场
Thousands of hip-hop fans are entering the arena right now,
来看世界最棒的霹雳舞团
ready to see the world's best b-boy crews,
今晚几乎是国家代表队参赛
and nearly every country's represented tonight.
嘿, 大家好, 我们是瑞奇和梅尔文
Hey, guys, it's your boys Rickie and Melvin.
我们为Kiss广播和Kiss电视台作实况报导
We are reporting live for Kiss Radio and Kiss TV.
我们在法国蒙彼利埃
We are in Montpellier in France.
谢谢你, 中国
Thank you, China.
我在世界街舞大赛现场
Right now, I'm inside at the Battle of the Year.
现场气氛十分热闹！
This atmosphere is explosive!
我一直在期待年度大赛
I've been waiting for this competition all yearlong.
参赛队伍来自世界各地
We got crews from all over the place.
是啊, 没错, 有法国队,
Yeah, that's right, we've got France,
德国队, 还有...
we've got Germany, we've got...
以色列, 巴西也来参赛
...Israel, we've got the Brazilians and of course,
当然有韩国队
the favorites, the Koreans.
今晚将会有惊人的发展
It's gonna be absolutely amazing tonight.
是啊, 但是法国队有主场优势
Yeah, but there's something to be said about home-court advantage.
我们在法国！
Yes. And right now, we're in France!
大家都关注着韩国刺客队
The crew that everybody's going after are the Seoul Assassins!
韩国舞团正处于巅峰状态
This Korean crew is on top of the mountain,
毫无疑问的是由"老油鬼"来领军
and they're unquestionably led by Fuel,
世界上最具传奇色彩的“霹雳舞团”！
one of the most legendary b-boys in the world!
不要忘记这种艺术的起源
But let us not forget where this art form all began.
是在哪儿, 泰伦斯？是美国！
Where was that, Terrence? In America!
我爱梦幻队, 我支持唐帝
I love the Dream Team, Dante is my boy.
我希望看到他们赢, 但你看,
I want to see them win, but look,
像是刚刚组团才15分钟而已
they've been together 15 minutes.
别的舞团已经在一起15年了
These other crews have been together 15 years.
我不知道他们要靠什么来获胜
I don't know if they got what it takes to win this thing.
掌声欢迎法国, 左岸舞团！
So give it up for France, the Left Bank Crew, y'all!
掌声欢迎德国队！
Give it up for Germany!
德国男孩, 志在必得
The German boys, they came for it.
以色列 ！
Israel!
让我们欢迎比利时队！
Let's welcome Belgium!
哇！你的舞者来斗舞了！
Wow! Your boys came to battle!
欢呼吧
Make some noise!
日本 ！
Japan!
为希腊队欢呼！
Make some noise for Greece!
巴西 ！
Brazil!
瑞士！
Switzerland!
泰国 ！
Thailand!
这些舞者真的很强壮, 身材好又敏捷
These boys are really strong, really lean and agile.
大家很看好这支舞团
A lot of buzz on this crew right here.
波兰 ！   台湾！
Poland! Taiwan!
让我们来瞧瞧最惊人的霹雳舞团
Right now we're witnessing the most amazing b-boys
进其所能的赢得这场比赛
doing absolutely everything they can to win this competition.
编织着血与泪的诗篇
They are sweating blood and tears.
台湾队
Taiwan
终于最精彩的来了！
Here we go again!
来自韩国的...
From Korea...
这是我的最爱...
It's the favorites...
首尔刺客！
Seoul Assassins!
正在表演的是...
l am witnessing the performance of...
他们正为了荣耀而战
They are fighting for their pride and honour.
这太疯狂了！
This is crazy!
太精采了, 兄弟！
Show stopping, man!
大家都看傻了！
They shutting this crowd down!
泰伦斯, 你见过这样的事情？
Terrence, have you ever seen anything like it?
哇！首尔刺客正在秀给我们看！
Wow! The Seoul Assassins are making a statement!
他们真是站在峰顶上的怪物
Man, they're the monsters on top of the mountain.
其他人只能争第二
Everybody else is fighting for second place.
偏偏就是有人不信邪
You don't want to be the crew that has to follow that!
如果梦幻队想赢, 就得使出浑身解数
If the Dream Team wants to win, they really gotta bring it.
这么喜欢鬼扯
Guess they liked it.
你们不想当老二, 是吧？
That is one tough act to follow, huh?
我可以站在这里说什么知难行易
I could stand here and tell you it's gonna be easy,
但我不会
but I won't.
事实是, 大家都不看好我们
Fact is, the odds and the audience are stacked against us.
但是, 兄弟们, 现在这些都不重要
But gentlemen, none of that matters now.
这种情况下, 这里是属于我们的天下
This situation, this place, is exactly where this team is supposed to be.
我们所做过的努力
Everything we've ever done in our lives,
我们做过的决定, 我们受的磨练
every decision we've made, every hour we've trained,
流过的每一滴汗水
every drop of sweat we spilled,
适时带领我们进入这个阶段
has led us to this stage, at this exact moment.
这是我们的命运, 给我们壮大的机会
It is our fate, and it's giving us a chance at greatness.
上场去把世界冠军夺回来
A chance to go out there and rip that stage back from the world champions.
变成我们的舞台！让大家为我们欢呼！
Make that stage ours! Make that audience ours!
荣耀的时刻到了, 兄弟们
Time to shine, gentlemen.
荣耀的时刻
Time to shine.
我们为此而生, 兄弟们
We were born for this moment, gentlemen.
没错!
Yeah. That's right.
一, 二, 三！
On three. One, two, three!
梦幻队！
Dream Team!
现在出场的是来自自由女神的国度
And now, from the land of Lady Liberty,
梦幻队！
the Dream Team!
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
看来大家很厌恶
This is some overt hating.
应该是昨晚发生的意外所造成的
I knew after the incident last night that it was gonna be ugly,
真是没想到会演变成这样
but I don't think anybody could have imagined this.
不, 不, 不, 搞到都没有朋友了
Nah, nah, nah, they don't have any friends here.
呦, 这是世界街舞大赛, 大家起码也要尊重一下比赛
Yo, this is the Battle of the Year. It's all about respect, man.
给点爱心
Show some love.
大家吵个不停, 兄弟
They ain't gonna stop, man.
搞得全场越来越难堪
A hard roll just got that much harder.
那就硬上吧
Let's do this shit.
风雨生信心
Amid a blizzard of boos,
由梦幻队的新队长, "敲敲"来打头阵
the Dream Team's new captain, Do Knock, kicks off the routine.
这是一个旅程
This is a journey
听声辨位
into sound.
一, 二
One, two.
一, 二, 三, 四
One, two, three, four.
舞步的主题是非常重要的
The theme of their routine is vital.
他们要跳什么故事呢?
What is the story they're telling us via the beat?
大家要用心体会！
The audience has to see the story!
按部就班的, 跳着旋转霓虹灯
They're going step for step, spin for spin.
这不是开玩笑, 跳着摇摆舞步
This is no joke, Sway.
和谐、连续、同步！
We're talking harmony, continuity, synchronicity!
1970年代
In the 1970s,
纽约的涂鸦, 饶舌和霹雳舞
New York graffiti, rapping, and breaking,
成为主要的代表特征
became the prime expressions
一个新的年轻次文化叫作嘻哈!
of a new young people's subculture called hip-hop.
T, 看看梦幻队
T, look at the Dream Team.
你从未见过完美同步
You never seen this before. They're in perfect sync.
帅啊！这是夺冠的前奏呀
Pop! They're starting to win them over!
真是令人不敢相信！
I can't believe it!
我是非裔美国人
I'm African-American.
我是古巴裔美国人
I'm Cuban-American.
我是以色列裔美国人
I'm an Israeli-American.
我是德裔美国人
I'm a German-American.
我是法裔美国人
I'm French-American.
我是日裔美国人
I'm Japanese-American.
我是爱尔兰裔美国人
I'm Irish-American.
我是俄罗斯裔美国人
I'm Russian-American.
我是伊朗裔美国人
I'm an Iranian-American.
西班牙裔美国人
Spanish-American.
我是意大利裔美国人
I'm an Italian-American.
哇！他们看不到, 却能动作一致！
Wow! They can't see, but yet they're moving in unison!
令人难以置信！
This is incredible!
这是一个旅程
This is a... This is a journey
听声辨位
into sound.
在过去的15年中, 人们说
For the last 15 years, people have said
美国的霹雳舞团自私, 自大和没有团队精神
the US b-boys are selfish, cocky and got no teamwork skills.
没这回事  没有
No more, my man, no more-
这正在是新的一天的到来！
We are watching the dawning of a new day!
梦幻队重建了新的印象
The Dream Team just destroyed it!
给美国霹雳舞者一个赞啦
Big ups to those American boys.
现在, 我不知道评审的看法
Now, I don't know if the judges
他们能不能挤进四强
are gonna put them in the final four,
但他们够资格进四强
but they deserve to go to the final four.
瑞奇, 一些世界上最伟大的“霹雳舞团”
So, Rickie, some of the world's greatest b-boys
在这里竞相吹嘘和充满民族自豪
are competing for bragging rights and national pride here
就在年度总冠军战里
at the Battle of the Year championship.
嘿, 结果出来了！
Hey, the scores are in!
最后四强在我手里发烫着
I got the final four in my hot hands.
快公布吧
Check this, check this.
好吧, 【世界街舞大赛】
Okay, Battle of the Year,
第一入围的是韩国队！
number one seed from Korea!
首尔刺客！
Seoul Assassins!
第二是...
Second seed is from...
法国队 ！
France!
排名第三的是...
Number three seed...
德国队！
from Germany!
好吧...最后, 但并非弱者...
Okay... Last, but not least...
美国队！
...the US of A!
先敬一下评审
So, a toast to the judges
跌破了一堆眼镜
whose jaws all hit the ground when they saw
干得好, 兄弟们
you guys perform today. Good job, fellas.
干杯
Cheers.
赞啦
That's right.
干杯
Cheers.
什么？
What?
噢, 老天啊
Oh, my God.
嘿
Hey.
宝宝在哪里？
Where's the baby?
在我妈那边
With my mom.
教练
Coach.
她是乔伦娜
Meet Jolene.
嗨, 很高兴见到你
Hi. So nice to meet you.
欢迎来到法国        谢谢
Pleasure. Welcome to France. Thanks.
你怎么有钱买机票？
Where'd you get the ticket?
大家送给你的蜜月礼物
We all chipped in. Consider it a honeymoon.
你看那个
Look at that.
回到比赛报导
Once again, it's on.
美国和德国都进了四强
The Americans and the Germans have made it to the final four.
左岸对抗梦幻队
Left Bank versus the Dream Team
斗赢的人才有权利说话
for the right to battle the reigning champion.
呀！
Yeah!
我们为观众解释一下评分方式
Sway, why don't we break down the scoring system for our viewers at home?
今晚的五位评审来自不同的国家
Now, we have five judges representing various countries here tonight.
每个评审10分
Each judge scores on a scale of one to 10,
加总最高50分
which means a perfect score is 50.
难以置信
Incredible.
梦幻队太赞了
The Dream Team is all over them.
哇, 左岸队情况不妙,  T.
Wow, Left Bank is looking desperate now, T.
还有, 泰伦斯！
And there it is, Terrence!
梦幻队获胜!
The Dream Team wins. They're going to the final battle.
美国人真的做到了
The Americans really did it.
他们将在总决赛中与韩国人一争高下
They will compete in the finals against the highly favored Koreans.
美国队刚刚离开了舞台
The American crew just left the stage and I have no words.
15年来第一次
For the first time in 15 years,
美国队终于有机会抱回世界冠军
the Americans have a chance to bring home a b-boy world championship
回到美国本土   街舞的起源地
back to American soil where it all began.
为什么每个人看起来都很紧张？
Why is everyone looking so nervous right now?
我们得到我们想要的, 对吧？
We got what we asked for, right?
我们要对韩国人？
Us against the Koreans?
整个世界都在盯着我们
And now the entire world is looking at us,
如果你问我, 我们怎么做到的
which, if you ask me, that's how it's supposed to be.
谁开创了霹雳舞新世界？
I mean, who created this whole b-boy thing?
我们做到了!         谁？
We did. Who?
我们做到了！没错!
We did! Exactly.
我们这一代已经跳不动了
I mean, our generation may have kicked this whole thing off,
圣火就在你们的手中
but torch is in your hands now.
只有一件事还没有做
So, really only one thing left to do.
把冠军给我带回家
Bring the crown home where it belongs.
办得到吗？
Can we do that?
可以!
Yes, sir.
可以吗？
I said, can we do that?
可以, 长官！
Yes, sir!
这是这样!
That's what I'm talking about.
两分钟后, 梦幻队
Two minutes, Dream Team.
喘口气
Breathe, gentlemen.
没什么话可说的了
Not that much left to say.
大家正等着老美出洋相
They're expecting ugly Americans out there.
跌破他们的眼镜
Let's show 'em who we really are.
跳的像个冠军
Act like champions.
我们就是冠军！
Be champions!
上吧!
Let's go.
女士们, 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
你们一直等待的时刻来临了！
The moment you've all been waiting for is here!
韩国队
So we got, from Korea,
鼓掌欢迎首尔刺客队！
please give it up for the Seoul Assassins!
美国梦幻队！
And from the US of A, Dream Team!
一, 二, 三！
One, two, three!
开始尬舞吧！
Let the battle begin!
这是我们的天下！  跳啊!
We got this! We got this! Let's go! Come on!
开战了!
And here we go.
世界街舞大赛开干!
The Battle of the Year is on.
"童童"和"叛徒", 使出了绝招
Kid and Rebel, they know how to bring the pain.
加油！
Come on, boys!
呀！
Yeah!
韩国使出了怪物舞技
Korea counters with a monster combo.
令人难以置信
Absolutely incredible.
瞧, 难怪跳不过韩国人
See, this is why the Koreans are considered unbeatable.
呀！
Yeah!
太神了
Man, that doesn't even seem humanly possible.
首尔刺客杀遍全场
Seoul Assassins are killing it.
好吧
Okay.
完美无瑕的整齐舞步
Flawless synchronization.
太屌了！这些人完全没有恐惧
Sick moves! These guys have no fear.
争夺世界霸权之战
This is a battle for world supremacy.
该死！
Damn!
哦, 我的上帝, 他们快把地板给掀了！
Oh, my God, they're ripping up the floorboards!
梦幻队也是花招尽出
The Dream Team's battling out of their minds,
大家都爱死了
and the crowd is loving it.
跳！尬！
Go! Come on!
"老油鬼" 单挑 "敲敲"！
Fuel calls out Do Knock!
"老油鬼"是顶尖高手
Fuel is calling for the best of the best.
"老油鬼"使出了百花齐放的绝招！
Fuel unleashes a series of lethal moves!
世界顶级的运动员, 高手中的高高手
You're watching a world-class athlete at the top of his game.
高招的舞步真是令人非常震惊
That kind of power move is mind-boggling.
呀！   敲敲！
Yeah! Do Knock!
敲敲！
Yeah, Do Knock!
"敲敲"回敬使出单手回旋！
Do Knock answers with one-handed rollbacks!
连续循环摇摆
Back and forth, Sway.
不分上下难分胜负
They're going blow for blow right now.
TJ, 第一次
TJ, for the first time,
刺客终于踢到铁板了！
the Assassins seem to be on their heels!
绝招尽出, 但时间也接近尾声
They're giving it everything they have, but time is winding down.
哦！
Oh!
哦, 宝贝, 美国队发动总攻击！
Oh, baby, the US strikes... Yes!
毁灭性的舞步！
...with a devastating move!
韩国队使出了空中杀阵！
Korea strikes back with an aerial assault!
令人震惊的, 太不可思议, 棒极了！
Electric, incredible, fantastic!
谁赢了？
Who won?
旗鼓相当! 平分秋色!
That right there was, pound for pound,
这是我这辈子见过最屌的尬舞!
the best battle I've ever seen in my life!
他们连吃奶的力气都使出来了
They have given absolutely everything on the stage. Their heart...
刚刚舞台上表演了他们的灵魂舞技
...their souls are on the stage just now.
美国！美国！美国！
USA! USA! USA!
谁才是世界街舞大赛的冠军？
Who will bring home the crown of Battle of the Year world champion?
我简直不敢相信我所看到的！
I can't believe what I saw!
你看到了吗？   究竟是什么状况？
Did you see that? What the hell?
真的分不出来谁才是赢家？
I really can't tell who the winner is, man. You?
冠军就要诞生了    我不知道, 我不知道
This is gonna be close. I don't know, I don't know.
哟, 分数出来了！
Yo, man, judges' scores are in!
首尔刺客只赢了一分
Seoul Assassins by one point.
泰伦斯, 韩国人赢了！
Terrence, the Koreans win!
该死的
Damn.
就差他妈的一分
One point. One goddamn point.
兄弟们
Well, gentlemen, here we are.
我想让你知道
I want you to know something.
我才不管分数差多少
I don't give a damn what that scoreboard says
金牌还是银牌
or what color the medal is they give you.
大家都值得骄傲
Proud of all of you.
教练, 你不用再安慰我们了
Come on, Coach, you don't have to sugar-coat it for us.
我们输了
We didn't accomplish what we came to do.
不是, "狙击手"
I wouldn't do that, Sniper.
兄弟们,
Look, fellas,
我不得不承认自己是一个幸运的人
all my life, I've had to consider myself a fortunate man.
世如棋局
I don't know, things just
这一路走来
kind of went my way.
两年前发生的变故
All that changed two years ago.
我在车祸中失去了我的妻子,  15岁的儿子
I lost my wife, 15-year-old boy in a car wreck.
而当我失去了我的家人
And when I lost my family,
我也迷失了自我
I lost my way.
我不知道, 我只是...
I don't know, I just...
自甘堕落
Well, I quit living.
你们都听我说过很多次了
You've all heard me say a million times,
“ 改变态度, 改变人生 ”
"Change how you think, change your life."
事实上是...
Fact is,
你们改变了我
you've changed the way I think.
你改变了我的人生
You've changed my life.
培训的第一天, 我有一个目标,
First day of training, I had one goal,
教导舞团如何整合成一个团队
teach a crew how to be a team.
没想到不仅如此
We became much more than that.
我们变成了一家人
We became a family.
有时我以为我将一蹶不振
Something I thought I'd lost forever.
成败论英雄
And win or lose, gentlemen,
当你有了家人
when you got family
输赢都不重要了
nothing else matters.
我们不甘心就这样结束, 教练
But it wasn't supposed to end like this, Coach.
这不是结束, 敲敲
It's not the ending, Do Knock.
这是开始
It's the beginning.
等等...
Wait.
明年还要来吗, 教练？
You coming back next year, Coach?
你在开玩笑吧？
You kidding me?
辛苦了半天只为争第二？
We did all this work to come in second?
第二名烂透了
Second sucks.
对啊
Damn right.
来! 靠过来!
Come on, let's huddle up one more time.
数三下
On three.
一, 二, 三！
One, two, three!
梦幻队！
Dream Team!
到底要看几遍啦？
Do we have to watch that whole thing?
不要关啦
No.
是啊,  山鸡说要关掉
Yeah, Roo's right. Take it off.
要是我去了, 我们就赢了
Hey, you guys needed me. If I was there, we would have won.
狗真的改不了吃屎
Once an asshole, always an asshole.
我只是说真话呀
I'm just saying.
少臭屁了？
Are you for real?
这家伙, 兄弟
This guy, man.
第二名没啥不好呀
Second place, there's nothing wrong with it.
啊就第二名啊
It's just second place.
兄弟们, 告诉他第二名怎样
Guys, tell him what we think about second.
第二名烂透了!
Second sucks.
没错
It sure does.
我也要参一咖啦...
I still wish I could have been there, though, man.
好啊, 看什么时候不用再撑拐杖？
You can be. How much time you got left on those crutches?
大约六个星期, 我就没事了
About six weeks, and I'll be ready. There it is.
其他的人, 我们有超过三个月的准备期
For the rest of us, though, since we got more than three months to prepare,
应该在周一就开始排练
we should start rehearsals on Monday.
什么？别闹了, 教练
What? Come on, Coach.
我们才刚回来耶~        好主意, 教练
We just got back. Good idea, Coach.
我们才刚回来!     教练, 真的吗？
We just got back, Coach. Really?
听好了
Listen up.
我的规则很简单
My rules are simple.
早上六点开始训练
Practice starts at 6:00 a.m.
谁敢超过六点....
Come at 6:01...
♪ I just can't live anymore like this
♪ My heart just opened up the door again
♪ Just watch me fly as I spread my wings
♪ Don't ask me why 'cause there are too many things.
♪ As your friend As your friend As your friend
♪ As your friend I woke up as your friend
♪ I just can't live anymore like this
♪ My heart just opened up the door again
♪ Just watch me fly as I spread my wings
♪ Don't ask me why 'cause there are too many things
♪ And now we're standing on the edge
♪ Looking like "Here we go again"
♪ I used to be your man but today
♪ I woke up as your friend ♪